You did a wonderful job. Wonderful.
干得漂亮。太漂亮了！
You did it. You did it!
你做到了。你居然做到了！
To continue, you've listened to a long and
complex case, murder in the first degree.
在（陪审团）合议前，你们已经聆听了冗长又
复杂的法庭审理，这是关于一级谋杀的案子。
Premeditated murder is the most serious
charge tried in our criminal courts.
在刑事法庭所审理的案件中，
谋杀罪是最严重的控诉。
You've listened to the testimony, had the
law interpreted as it applies in this case.
你们听取了证词，理解了本案所适用的法律。
It's now your duty to sit down and try
and separate the facts from the fancy.
现在你们要做的就是坐下来，把案件事实与
虚构相剥离，并进行认定。
One man is dead.
Another man's life is at stake.
一人死亡。另一个命悬一线。
If there's a reasonable doubt in your
minds as to the guilt of the accused -
如果你们认为对被告人的罪行存在合理怀疑――
a reasonable doubt-then you must
bring me a verdict of not guilty.
合理怀疑――那么你们必须作出无罪认定。
If there's no reasonable doubt,
then you must, in good conscience,
如果不存在合理怀疑，那么依良心，你们必须
find the accused guilty.
认定被告人有罪。
However you decide,
your verdict must be unanimous.
不管如何认定，你们的裁决必须一致。
In the event that
you find the accused guilty,
如果你们认定被告人有罪，
the bench will not entertain
a recommendation for mercy.
本席不会建议要怜悯被告人。
The death sentence is mandatory
in this case.
本案要强制适用死刑。
You are faced with a grave responsibility.
Thank you, gentlemen.
你们肩负的责任重如泰山。
各位先生，谢谢你们。
The alternate jurors are excused.
候补陪审员可以离开了。
The jury will now retire.
陪审团现在退庭。
- Wanna piece of gum?
- 要口香糖吗？
- No, thanks.
- 不用，谢谢。
This thing isn't movin'.
这东西挪不动了。
- I'll give you a hand.
- 我来帮你。
- That's it.
- 好了。
You know somethin'? I called
the Weather Bureau this morning.
知道吗？早上我给气象局打了个电话。
This is gonna be
the hottest day of the year.
今天会是今年最热的一天。
You'd think they'd air-condition this place.
本想这里会有空调。
- What is your name, sir?
- 先生，您叫什么名？
- Oh, it's... that one. Yeah.
- 噢，我叫…这个。对。
Thank you very much.
OK, gentlemen. Everybody's here.
非常感谢！好的，先生们，都到齐了。
Now, if there's anything you want,
I'll be right outside the door. Just knock.
嗯，如果你们需要什么，我就在门外静候。敲门就行。
Good morning.
I never knew they locked the door.
早上好。我没想到他们会把门关上。
Sure they lock the door.
What'd you think?
当然，他们会关上门的。你以为呢？
I don't know. It just never occurred to me.
我不知道啊。我还没碰到过呢。
- What's that for?
- 那是干嘛用的？
- I thought we might wanna vote by ballot.
- 我想我们可能要投票表决。
Great idea. Maybe we can
get him elected senator.
好主意。也许我们可以选他做议员。
- How'd you like it?
- 陪审有何感受？
- I don't know. It was pretty interesting.
- 不知道啊。感觉很有意思。
- Yeah? I almost fell asleep.
- 是吗？我都快睡着了。
- I mean, I've never been on a jury before.
- 我的意思是，我还从未担任过陪审员。
No? I've sat on many juries.
没做过？我都做好多回了。
Those lawyers talk and talk, even when
it's an open-and-shut case like this one.
那些律师口若悬河、雄辩滔滔，即使审理的只是
像本案一样一清二楚的案子。
- Ever hear so much talk about nothin'?
- 你见过这么多没话找话的吗？
- I guess they're entitled.
- 我认为这是他们的权利。
They're entitled. It's the system, but...
他们是有权利。规定是这样规定，不过……
if you ask me, I'd slap those tough kids
down before they start any trouble.
要是你问我，我会在这帮调皮蛋惹祸之前就把
他们整得俯首帖耳。
It saves a lot of time and money.
Let's get started.
这样可以省掉大量的时间和金钱。
我们开始吧。
Yeah.Let's get started. We've probably all
got things to do here.
好，开始吧。我们可能要在这里把事情全部搞定。
We can start with a five-minute break.
One gentleman is in the bathroom.
我们可以休息五分钟再开始。
有人去上厕所了。
Are... we gonna sit in order?
我们要按顺序就座吗？
Gee, I don't know. I guess so.
啊，不清楚啊。可能是这样子吧。
- Buddy, you're in my seat.
- 老兄，你坐的是我的位置。
- Oh, excuse me.
- 噢，对不起。
That's all right.
没关系。
Hey, that's not a bad view, huh?
嗨，那边的风景还不错，是吧？
What did you think of the case?
I mean, it had a lot of interest for me.
你对这个案子是怎么看的？
我是说，我对这个案子很感兴趣。
No real... dead spots.
You know what I mean?
很少见……死亡现场。
明白我的意思吗？
We were lucky to get a murder case.
I figured us for an assault or burglary.
我们很幸运，陪审的是谋杀案件。
我以为我们陪审的会是伤害案或是盗窃案呢。
Boy, they can be the dullest!
老兄，那会无聊死的。
- Hey, is that the Woolworth Building?
- 嗨，那是伍尔沃斯大楼吗？
- That's right.
- 是的。
Isn't that funny? I've lived here all my life.
I've never been inside it.
我在这里住了一辈子，可是我还没进过那座大楼。
是不是很可笑？
If you had to sort out all that junk,
like that thing with the movies.
假如你要清理掉那堆垃圾，就像电影里演的那样。（翻译得不准确-_-）
Yeah. What about that business with the knife?
是呀。那把刀怎么解释？
Asking grown-up people to believe that kind of jazz.
要一帮成年人相信那堆废话。
You expect that.
You know what we're dealing with.
等着瞧吧。你知道我们在干嘛。
Yeah, I guess so.
就是，我也这样认为。
Well, your horn works.
Now try your lights.
天啊，你家的警报响了。赶紧查查你家的电灯。
（擤鼻涕太响了，就像警报响了。幽默一下^_^)
- You got a cold?
- 你感冒了？
- And how. Hot-weather colds can kill you.
- 怎么会呢。热天感冒会要了你的小命。
I can hardly touch my nose.
Know what I mean?
我都不敢碰我的鼻子了。明白我的意思吗？
Sure do. I just got over one.
当然了。我刚刚经历一场。
- Oh, come on! Mr Foreman, let's go.
- 奥，快点！主席先生，我们开始吧。
- The guy's still in the bathroom.
- 那人还在厕所呢。
What's new? I didn't get a chance
to see a paper this morning.
有啥新闻？我还没机会看今早的报纸。
I was only wondering
how the market closed.
我只是纳闷怎么会停市了呢。
- You got a seat on the exchange?
- 你在交易所做事？
- I'm a broker.
- 我是经纪人。
I run a messenger service.
我经营一家通讯服务企业。
The Beck and Call Company.
贝克・卡尔公司。
The name is my wife's idea.
我爱人想的名称。
Got 37 men workin'. Started with nothin'.
公司有37名员工。我是白手起家。
OK, men. Let's take our seats, huh?
好了，同志们(^_^)。各就各位，好吧？
We can all get out of here pretty quick.
I have tickets to that ball game tonight.
我们很快就可以闪人了。我买了今晚球赛的门票。
Yanks and Cleveland. We've got
this kid Modjelewski in there.
洋基队对克里夫兰队。我们有Modjelewski这小子。
He's a real bull, this kid. You know...
这小子势如奔牛。知道吧……
Real jug-handled. You know?
真是条汉子。知道吧？
You're a real baseball fan, aren't ya?
Where do we sit here?
你是铁杆棒球迷，你不是吗？(^_^戴眼镜的无动于衷)
我们怎么入座？
I thought we'd sit in order,
by jury numbers.
我们按陪审员编号入座。
One, two, three and so on around the
table, if that's OK with you gentlemen.
1，2，3如此类推，围着桌子坐下，如果你们不反对的话。
- What's the difference?
- 有什么区别吗？
- It's reasonable to sit in order.
- 按顺序就座很合理。
- Let it be.
- 那就这样。
- That's twelve. We go around one, two...
- 一共12个人。我们按这个顺序围着坐下。
What was your impression
of the prosecuting attorney?
你对检察官的印象如何？
- I beg pardon?
- 抱歉。
- I thought he was really sharp,
- 我觉得他很牛X，
the way he handled all those points
one by one, in logical sequence.
他一一陈述他的观点，很有条理。
- I was very impressed.
- 印象深刻。
- I think he... he did an expert job.
- 我认为他…他表现得很出色。
A lot of drive, too. You know? Real drive.
他轮番进攻，给对手很大压力。
OK, fellas. Can we
hold it down a minute? Fellas?
好，同志们，能安静一下吗，同志们？
Say, we'd like to get started.
嗯，我们要开始合议了。
Gentleman at the window.
窗边的那位同志。
- We'd like to get started.
- 我们要开始合议了。
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- 奥，不好意思。
- The kid kills his father, just like that.
- 那小子手刃生父，事实就是这样。
- Listen, it happens all the time.
- 这样的事在所难免。
They let those kids run wild up there.
他们让这帮小子在外面撒野。
Well, maybe it serves him right.
You know what I mean?
嗯，或许他有权决定自己怎么生活。
你懂我的意思吗？
- Is everyone here?
- 大伙儿都在了吧？
- The old man is inside.
- 老先生在里面呢。
- Would you knock on the door for him?
- 你能敲门叫一下他吗？
- Yeah.
- 没问题。
- Are you a Yankee fan?
- 你是鸡丝吗（洋基队的粉丝别拍我哈^_^）
- No, Baltimore.
- 不是，我是拔丝（巴尔的摩队的粉丝）
Baltimore?
巴尔的摩队的？
That's like being hit in the head
with a crowbar once a day.
那不是天天像被用铁棍打脑袋！
（嘲笑巴尔的摩队经常败北，而且输得很惨）
Who have they got? Who have they got
besides good groundkeepers?
他们有什么牛X的队员？除了不错的保洁员，
巴队还有什么牛人！
- Say, we'd like to get started.
- 嗯，我们要开始合议了。
- Forgive me, gentlemen.
- 请原谅，同志们。
- I didn't mean to keep you waiting.
- 让你们久等了。
- Baltimore?
- 巴尔的摩？
OK, if I can have your attention. You fellas
can handle this thing any way you want.
好了，请大家安静一下。大家可以按自己喜欢的方式进行合议。
I'm... you know,
I'm not gonna make any rules.
我……你们知道，我不会立下什么规则的。
We can, well, discuss it first, then vote
on it. That's, of course... that's one way.
嗯，我们可以先讨论，然后投票。
那是，当然……那是一种方式而已。
And, well, we can vote on it right now.
或者，我们可以直接投票。
I think it's customary
to take a preliminary vote.
先进行预测性投票，这是通常做法。
Yeah, let's vote. Who knows?
Maybe we can all get outta here.
好，那我们投票吧。天知道，也许我们一会儿就可以走人了。
（这家伙还惦记着球赛呢）
OK. Then I think that you know that we
have a first-degree murder charge here,
好吧，我想大家很清楚，这是一起一级谋杀案，
and if we vote the accused guilty,
we've got to send him to the chair.
如果我们投票认定被告人有罪，被告人就得坐电椅了。
（美国通过坐电椅实施死刑）
Um... That's mandatory.
恩……这是强制性的。
- I think we know that.
- 这点我们都清楚。
- Yeah, let's see who's where.
- 是啊，大家表态吧。
- OK. Anyone doesn't wanna vote?
- 好。谁不愿投票？
- It's fine with me.
- 我没意见。
OK, then, just remember that this
has to be twelve to nothing, either way.
好的，别忘了投票结果要12：0，或是0：12.
（陪审团的意见要一致）
That's the law. OK, are we ready?
法律是这么规定的。好，可以开始了吗？
All those voting guilty,
please raise your hands.
认为有罪的，请举手。
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven...
1，2，3，4，5，6，7……
eight, nine, ten, eleven.
8，9，10，11.
OK, that's eleven guilty.
好，11个人认为有罪。
Those voting not guilty?
谁认为无罪？
One. Right.
一个。好的。
Eleven guilty, one not guilty.
Well, now we know where we are.
十一个认为有罪，一个认为无罪。
嗯，现在我们知道各自的立场了。
Boy, oh boy! There's always one.
同志啊同志！总有一个要和组织意见相左。
So, what do we do now?
那，我们现在怎么办？
- I guess we talk.
- 我们讨论一下吧。
- Boy, oh boy!
- 同志啊同志！
You really think he's innocent?
你真的认为他是无辜的？
- I don't know.
- 我不知道。
- You sat in court with the rest of us.
- 你和大家是一块儿听审的啊。
You heard what we did.
The kid's a dangerous killer.
你听到我们刚说的了。这小子是个危险分子。
- He's 18 years old.
- 他才18岁啊。
- Well, that's old enough.
- 哼，已经够大的了。
He stabbed his own father
four inches into the chest.
他手刃生父，胸部的伤口有四尺深。
They proved it
a dozen different ways in court.
他们在法庭上用各种方法证明了。
- Would you like me to list 'em for you?
- 你要我给你一条一条列出来吗？
- No.
- 不必了。
- Then what do you want?
- 那你要干啥？
- I just want to talk.
- 我只是想讨论一下。
What's there to talk about?
Eleven of us think he's guilty.
有啥好讨论的？我们十一个人认为他死有余辜。
No one had to think about it twice
except you.
除了你，没人要思虑再三。
I want to ask you something.
Do you believe his story?
我想问一下你。你相信他说的吗？
- I don't know. Maybe I don't.
- 我不知道。也许不信。
- So how come you voted not guilty?
- 那你为啥要投无罪票？
There were eleven votes for guilty.
十一个人认为有罪哪。
It's not easy to raise my hand and send a
boy off to die without talking about it first.
我不能轻易举手，不经讨论就把一个小孩送上黄泉路。
- Well, now, who says it's easy?
- 嗯，有谁说这很容易了？
- No one.
- 没人说。
What? Just because I voted fast?
I honestly think the guy is guilty.
啥？就因为我表态太快吗？我确实认为他罪有应得。
Couldn't change my mind
if you talked for 100 years.
就算你嚼烂舌根，我也不会改变我的观点。
I'm not trying to change your mind.
It's just that...
我没想过要改变你的观点。只是……
This is somebody's life.
We can't decide in five minutes.
事关人命，我们不能草率下决定。
- Supposing we're wrong?
- 假设我们错了？
- Supposing this building fell on my head?
- 假设天花板砸我头上吧？
- You can suppose anything.
- 你可以假设一切。
- That's right.
- 没错。
What's the difference how long it takes?
Supposin' we take five minutes? So what?
下决定的时间长短有啥区别？
如果我们用五分钟就下定论了，那有怎么了？
Let's take an hour. The ball game
doesn't start till eight o'clock.
我们花一小时吧。球赛要到8点才开始呢。
- Who's got something to say?
- 谁有话要说？
- /'m willing to sit for an hour.
- 我愿意坐等一小时。
- Great. I heard a good story last night...
- 那太好了。我昨晚听到一个不错的故事……
- That's not why we're sitting here.
- 我们来这里不是要听讲故事的。
All right, then you tell me.
What are we sitting here for?
那好，那你告诉我。我们在这干坐着干嘛？
I don't know. Maybe no reason.
我不知道。也许没有原因。
Look, this kid's been
kicked around all of his life.
听我说，那小孩生下来就没人疼没人爱。
You know, born in a slum,
mother dead since he was nine.
生在贫民区，九岁就没娘了。
He lived for a year and a half
in an orphanage
他在孤儿院里生活了一年半，
when his father was serving
a jail term for forgery.
那会儿他爹因伪造文件犯事，正在坐牢。
That's not a very happy beginning.
他这一生就没起个好头。
He's a wild, angry kid. That's all
he's ever been. And you know why?
他性格狂野、愤世。他一向如此。你知道为啥吗？
Cos he's been hit on the head
by somebody once a day, every day.
因为他每天都被别人欺负。
He's had a pretty miserable 18 years.
I think we owe him a few words, that's all.
18年来他度日如年。我想我们要为他说啥。就这样。
I don't mind telling you this, mister. We
don't owe him a thing. He got a fair trial.
先生，我要告诉你，我们不欠他什么。对他的审理很公平。
What do you think that trial cost?
He's lucky he got it. Know what I mean?
你要怎样审理才得？他应该庆幸法庭很公正。明白我的意思吗？
Look, we're all grown-ups in here.
We heard the facts, didn't we?
听我说，我们不是一两岁的小孩了。事实我们是知道的吧？
You're not gonna tell me we're supposed
to believe this kid, knowing what he is.
你该不会要我们相信那小子吧。
他的为人，我们是一清二楚的。
I've lived among them all my life.
我跟他这种人打了一辈子交道。
You can't believe a word they say.
You know that. I mean, they're born liars.
这种人信口雌黄。我是说，他们这种人天生就是骗子。
- Only an ignorant man can believe that.
- 只有蠢蛋才会相信。
- Now, listen...
- 现在，听我说……
Do you think you were born
with a monopoly on the truth?
你认为你天生就垄断真理了吗？
I think certain things should be
pointed out to this man.
有些事情应该跟这位同志说清楚。
- It's not Sunday. We don't need a sermon.
- 今天不是礼拜日，不要在这儿布道了。
- We have a job to do. Now let's do it.
- 我们有事要做呢。我们开始处理吧。
Rice Pops. It's a product
I work on at the agency.
爆米花筒。这是个产品。
我在一个机构里做事。
"The breakfast with the built-in bounce."
“爆米声声吃早点。”
- I wrote that line.
- 那句是我写的。
- Very catchy.
- 朗朗上口啊！
- Say, do you mind?
- 嗯，能静一下吗？
- I'm sorry. I have this habit of doodling.
- 抱歉，我习惯乱写乱画。
- It keeps me thinking clearly.
- 这样我思路清晰。
- We have work to do.
- 我们还有事情要处理。
There's no point
staying here for ever. OK.
在这不能没个主题。好了。
Perhaps if the gentleman down there who
is disagreeing with us could tell us why.
或许持不同意见的那位同志能告诉我们不赞同的理由。
Tell us what you're thinking. We might be
able to show you where you're mixed up.
跟我们说说你的想法。或许我们可以找出你在打了岔。
Maybe this is an idea. It seems to me that
it's up to us to convince this gentleman
也许可以这样，我们来说服这位同志
that he's wrong and we're right. Maybe if
we each took a couple of minutes just to...
他站错了队伍，我们才是正确的。如果我们没人话几分钟去……
- Well, it was just a quick idea.
- 嗯，这只是拍脑袋想出来的。
- No, no, no. That's a good one.
- 没有，没有，没有。这主意不错。
Supposing we go once around the table?
那我们轮流来吧？
I guess you're first.
你先来吧。
It's hard to put into words.
这不好说啊。
I just think he's guilty.
我只是认为他有罪。
I thought it was obvious from the word go.
Nobody proved otherwise.
我想事情是明摆着的，没人有相反的证明。
Nobody has to prove otherwise.
The burden of proof's on the prosecution.
没人有义务去做相反的证明。举证责任在公诉一方。
The defendant doesn't even have to open
his mouth. That's in the Constitution.
甚至被告人可以保持沉默。这宪法里有规定。
Sure, I know that. What I meant was...
当然，我知道这个。我是说……
Well... I just think he's guilty.
I mean, somebody saw him do it.
嗯……我只是认为他有罪。我是说，有人看到他杀人了。
OK. Here's what I think. And I have
no personal feelings about this.
好了，这就是我的想法。我对本案不带个人偏见。
I just wanna talk about facts.
我只想说下事实。
Number one.
第一：
The old man lived downstairs under
the room where the killing took place.
那老人住在案发房间的楼下。
At 10 minutes after 12 on the night
of the killing, he heard loud noises.
案发当晚，零点十分，他听到一阵吵闹。
Said it sounded like a fight.
他说听起来像是打架。
And he heard the kid yell out
"I'm gonna kill ya."
他还听到那小孩叫嚣“老子弄死你”。
A second later,
he heard a body hit the floor.
不一会儿，他听到身体落地的声音。
Ran to the door, opened it up, saw the kid
run down the stairs and out of the house.
他就跑去开门，看见那小孩朝楼梯下跑，夺门而出。
Called the police. They found the old man
with the knife in his chest.
他报了警。警察找到那个老头，胸口插着把刀。
The coroner fixed the time of death
around midnight.
验尸官断定死亡时间是午夜左右。
Now, these are facts.
You can't refute facts. The kid is guilty.
嗯，这些是事实。你不能否认事实。那小孩是有罪的。
I'm just as sentimental as the next fella.
I know he's only 18.
我和左手边的这位同志一样感性。
我知道他只有18岁。
- But he's still gotta pay for what he did.
- 但是他还是要为他的所作所为负责。
- I'm with you.
- 我同意。
- OK. Are you finished?
- 那好。你说完了吗？
- Yeah.
- 说完了。
It is obvious to me that
the boy's entire story was flimsy.
很明显，这小孩的说辞不足信。
He claimed he was at the movies,
他说他当时在电影院，
yet he couldn't remember the names
of the films he saw or who played in them.
但他记不得电影的名字，也记不得演员是谁。
- That's right.
- 是这样子。
- And no one saw him at the theatre.
- 而且没人看到他在电影院。
And the woman across the street-if her
testimony don't prove it, nothing does.
此外，穿街而过的那位妇女，如果连她的证词都不能证明，
那其他的都证明不了了。
- That's right. She actually saw the killing.
- 就是啊。她确实看见杀人了。
- Fellas, please. Let's go in order.
- 同志们，请一个一个地说。
Just a minute. Here's a woman...
等会儿。有个女人……
Here's a woman who's lying in bed.
She can't sleep. She's dyin' with the heat.
有个女人躺在床上，辗转难眠，快被热死了。
She looks out the window,
and right across the street
她望出窗外，正好是当街对过
she sees the kid stick the knife
into his father.
她看见那小孩把刀捅他父亲。
The time is 12.10 on the nose.
Everything fits.
时间正好是0：10。一切吻合。
She's known the kid all his life.
她是从小看他长大的。
His window is opposite hers across the
el tracks. She swore she saw him do it.
两家窗户相对，中间隔着高架铁轨。她发誓她没有看走眼。
Through the windows
of a passing el train.
窗外正好有轻轨通过。
This el train had no passengers on it.
It was just being moved downtown.
轻轨上没有旅客，它只是正好开往市中心。
The lights were out,remember?
and they proved in court that at night
灯都灭了，还记得吧？
法庭上他们证明了晚上的时候，
you can look through the windows and
see what's happening on the other side.
可以透过窗户，看见对面的一举一动。
- They proved it.
- 他们已经证明了。
- I'd like to ask you something.
- 我想问你一下。
You don't believe the boy.
How come you believe the woman?
你连这小孩都不相信，你怎么相信这个女人？
She's one of "them" too, isn't she?
她也是“他们”中的一个，不是吗？
- You're a pretty smart fella, aren't ya?
- 你反应是相当的快啊，不是吗？
- OK, gentlemen. Now, gentlemen.
- 好了，同志们。听着，同志们。
- Come on, sit down. Sit down.
- 够了，坐下，坐下。
- What's he so wise about? I'm telling ya...
- 他干嘛这么聪明？我告诉你……
Come on. Now we're not gonna
get anywhere fighting.
好了，我们不是来打口水战的。
- Whose turn is it next?
- 下个轮到谁了？
- Oh, his. Number five.
- 奥，到他了。五号。
May I... Can I pass?
我可以……我能不说吗？
Well... That's your privilege.
嗯……那是你的权利。
How about the next gentleman?
下一位同志呢？
Oh. Well... I don't know.
奥，嗯……我不知道。
I started to be convinced,
you know, very early in the case.
我有点儿动摇了。案子一开始，我
You see, I was looking for a motive.
嗯，我就寻找犯罪动机。
That's very important because if you don't
have a motive, where's your case, right?
这很重要，因为如果没有犯罪动机，就不会犯案，对吧？
Anyway, that testimony from those people
across the hall from the kid's apartment,
不管怎样，经过那小孩房间的那些证人提供的证词
that was very powerful. Didn't they say
something about a fight, an argument,
很有力。他们不是说当晚7点左右听到他们父子之间
between the old man and his son
around about seven o'clock that night?
发生争吵、打架之类的吗？
- I could be wrong but...
- 我可能错了，不过……
- It was eight o'clock, not seven.
- 是8点，不是7点。
They heard an argument. Then
they heard the father hit the boy twice.
他们听见争吵。接着听到父亲两次打儿子。
Finally they saw the boy run, angry,
out of the house. What does that prove?
最后，他们看见那小孩愤怒的跑出房间。这证明了什么呢？
It don't prove anything.
It's just part of the picture.
这证明不了什么。这只不过是事件的部分过程。
You said it provided a motive.
So did the prosecution.
你说这引发了犯罪动机。检方也是这么认为。
That wasn't a very strong motive.
那样的动机并不强烈。
This boy has been hit so many times
that violence is practically...
这小孩经常别打，家庭暴力是家常便饭了……
It's a normal state of affairs with him.
那已经是他正常的心理状态了。
I just can't see two slaps in the face
provoking him into committing murder.
我不相信两个耳光就能让他心生歹念，杀害生父。
It may have been two too many.
Everyone has a breaking point.
可能不只两次。谁都有忍无可忍的时候。
Anything else?
还有其他的吗？
- No.
-没了。
- OK. How about you?
-那好。你有要说的吗？
I don't know. It's all been said.
我不知道。都被说遍了。
You can talk here for ever.
It's still the same thing.
就算你磨破了嘴皮，也改变不了事实。
This kid is five for 0.
Well, look at his record.
现在是5：0啊。好吧，我们看看他的前科。
When he was 10, he was in children's
court: He threw a rock at a teacher.
10岁就被送上少年法庭，因为用石头砸老师。
When he was 15, he was
in reform school: He stole a car.
15岁进少年感化学校，因为偷车。
He's been arrested for muggin'.
He was picked up twice for knife fightin'.
因为抢劫被捕，因为携带凶器斗殴两次被拘。
They say he's real handy with a knife.
Oh, this is a very fine boy.
他们说看见他手拿刀具。哈，他真是三好少年啊！
Ever since he was five, his father
beat him up regularly. He used his fists.
打他从5岁开始，他老爸就经常教训他，用拳打脚踢啊！
So would I. A kid like that?
有这样的孽障，我也会。
It's these kids -
the way they are nowadays.
现在的小孩都这样。
When I was a kid,
I used to call my father "sir".
我小时候，我管我爸叫“先生”。
That's right.sir. Ever hear a kid
call his father that any more?
真的叫先生。你们现在还能听到小孩这么称呼老爸的吗？
Fathers don't seem to think
it's important any more.
现在的父亲好像觉得这不重要了。
- You got any kids?
- 你家里有小孩吗？
- Three.
- 3个。
I got one.
我有一个。
He's 22 years old.
他已经22岁了。
When he was nine years old,
he ran away from a fight.
他9岁的时候，跟别人打架，居然做了逃兵！
I saw it. I was so embarrassed,
I almost threw up.
我亲眼看见，当时就想找个缝钻进去。太让我失望了。
I said "I'm gonna make a man out of you
if I have to break you in two tryin'."
我跟他说“要是有第二次，我一定要让你像个男人一样”。
Well, I made a man out of him.
幸好，他确实有点儿男子汉的气概了。
When he was 16, we had a fight.
他16岁时，我们爷俩打了一架。
Hit me in the jaw. He was a big kid.
他朝我下巴就是一拳。那时他很大了。
I haven't seen him for two years.
我已经有两年没见过他了。
Kids.
小孩啊……
You work your heart out...
让人呕心沥血啊……
- Well, let's get goin'.
- 哈，扯远了。
- I think we're missing the point.
- 我们回到正题吧。
This boy's the product of a broken home
and a filthy neighbourhood.
这小孩的家庭支离破碎，邻里又是一片乌烟瘴气。
We can't help that. We're here
to decide his innocence or guilt,
我们是爱莫能助。我们今天来是认定他有罪还是无罪的。
not to go into the reasons
why he grew up the way he did.
不要纠缠于他成长的环境。
He was born in a slum.
Slums are breeding grounds for criminals.
他生于贫民区。贫民区是犯罪的温床。
It's no secret that children from slums
are potential menaces to society. I think...
贫民区里的小孩对社会是潜在的威胁，这不是什么秘密。我觉得啊……
You can say that again. The kids who
crawl out of these places are real trash.
说的没错。从这种地方爬出来的人纯粹就是社会败类。
- I don't want any part of them.
- 我对这类人是避之唯恐不及。
- Listen, I... I've lived in a slum all my life.
- 等等，我……我一直住在贫民区。
- Wait a minute.
- 等等。
- Please. I...
- 先听我说。我……
I've played in back yards
that were filled with garbage.
我小时候在堆满废物的后院玩耍。
- Maybe you can still smell it on me.
- 可能你现在还能从我身上闻到那种味道。
- Listen, sonny...
- 同志，听我说……
Come on, now. There's nothing personal.
拜托，那不是针对你。
Come on, fella. He didn't mean you.
Let's not be so sensitive.
好同志，他不是说你。不要太敏感。
This sensitivity I can understand.
我理解他的敏感。
OK, look. Let's stop the arguing.
We're only wasting time.
好了，不要再争执不休了。这样纯粹是浪费时间。
Your turn down there. Let's go.
我们继续。那位同志，轮到你了。
I didn't expect a turn. I thought
you were all gonna to try to convince me.
没我的事吧。我以为你们准备要把我说服呢。
- That was the idea.
- 就是这么打算的。
- I forgot. He's right.
- 我忘了。他说的没错。
He's the one keeping us in here.
Let's hear what he's got to say.
就他一个人把大伙儿在这干等。
我们听听他有什么高见。
Wait. We decided to do this a certain way.
I think we ought to stick to it.
等等。我们刚决定了认定的程序。我们应该按决定进行。
Oh, stop being a kid, will ya?
奥，别太小孩了，好吧？
- What do you mean, a kid?
- 小孩，你什么意思？
- What do you think I mean? K-I-D: Kid.
- 你觉得是什么意思？K-I-D：小孩。
Just because I'm trying
to keep this organised?
就因为我要有条不紊的进行？
Here, you take on the responsibility.
I'll just keep my mouth shut.
你来，你负责组织。我保持缄默。
- Why are you gettin' so hot? Calm down.
- 火气怎么那么大？消消气。
- Don't tell me to calm down.
- 别叫我消气。
You want to take the chair?
Take the chair.
你想坐这是吗？那坐吧。
Did you ever see such a thing?
你们见过这种人吗？
- You think it's funny?
- 你觉得好玩是吗？
- Forget it, fella. It's unimportant.
- 同志，算了，小事一桩。
Unimportant? Here, you try it.
小事？来，你负责。
Nobody wants to change.
You're doing a beautiful job.
没人要换人，你组织得很好。
Yeah, you're doin' great. Just great, fella.
You stay in there and pitch.
是啊，你做得很出色。同志，很出色。
你就坐下继续负责组织。
All right, let's hear from somebody.
好了，我们听听其他人怎么说。
Well, if you want me to tell you
how I feel about it, it's all right with me.
嗯，你要是想让说说我的想法，我没意见。
- Boy, I don't care what you do.
- 你要干嘛我不在乎。
- All right. I don't have anything brilliant.
- 好吧，我也没有什么高深的想法。
I only know as much as you do.
我知道的你们也知道。
According to the testimony,
the boy looks guilty. Maybe he is.
从证据上看，小孩好像是有罪。可能他确实有罪。
I sat there in court for six days
listening while the evidence built up.
我在法院呆了6天，听各方举证。
Everybody sounded so positive.
众口一词。
I began to get a peculiar feeling about
this trial. I mean, nothing is that positive.
我开始质疑本案的审理。我是说，并没有确凿的证据。
There are questions I'd have liked to ask.
Maybe they wouldn't mean anything but...
有些问题我想请教一下，可能没有什么意义，但是……
I felt that the defence wasn't conducting
a thorough enough cross-examination.
我觉得交叉质询时，辩方没有充分把握。
He let too many things go by-little things.
他错过了很多机会――一些机会。
What little things?
When they don't ask questions,
什么机会啊？他们不发问，
it's because they know
the answers already.
因为他们知道答案不言自明。
It's also possible for a lawyer to be just
plain stupid, isn't it? I mean, it's possible.
也有可能是律师太愚蠢了，不是吗？我是说，有可能。
You sound like you met
my brother-in-law once.
好像你见过我小舅子似的
（意思是说他小舅子也很笨^_^）
I kept putting myself in the kid's place.
I'd have asked for another lawyer, I think.
如果我是这小孩，我就另请高明了。
I mean, if I was on trial for my life,
我是说，如果我可能被判出死刑，
I'd want my lawyer to tear the prosecution
witnesses to shreds, or at least try to.
我希望我的律师把检方的证人问得理屈词穷，或者至少努力这样。
Look, there was one alleged
eyewitness to this killing.
比如说，检方有一个目击证人。
Someone else claims he heard the killing,
saw the boy run out after,
还有人说听见了杀人，接着看见被告人逃跑，
and there was circumstantial evidence.
还有间接证据。
But those two witnesses
were the entire case for the prosecution.
但那两个证人是检方的全部筹码。
Supposing they're wrong?
假设这两证人是错的呢？
What do you mean? What's the point
of having witnesses at all?
什么意思？那还要证人干嘛？
- Could they be wrong?
- 他们有没有可能出错？
- Those people were under oath.
- 证人已经宣过誓了。
They're only people. People
make mistakes. Could they be wrong?
他们也是人啊，是人就会犯错。他们就不会犯错吗？
- Well, no. I don't think so.
- 嗯，不会，我不这么看。
- Do you know so?
- 你确定？
Nobody can know a thing like that.
This isn't an exact science.
没人清楚这种事情，这又不是什么精确的科学问题。
That's right, it isn't.
说的没错，这确实不是科学问题。
OK, let's get to the point.
好了，我们回到正题吧。
What about the switch knife
they found in the old man's chest?
死者胸口上的那把弹簧刀又怎么解释？
Some people haven't talked yet.
Shouldn't we go in order?
还有人没说呢。能不能按顺序来？
They'll get a chance to talk.
Be quiet a second, will ya?
他们会有机会说的。先安静一下，行不行你？
What about the knife this fine, upright boy
admitted buying the night of the killing?
这位正直的三好少年承认他在案发当晚买的这把刀，又怎么解释？
- Let's talk about it.
- 我们讨论一下这个问题。
- All right. Let's get it in here and look at it.
- 好，把刀拿进来，大伙儿瞅瞅。
- I'd like to see it again. Mr Foreman?
- 我想再见识见识那把刀。组长先生？
- Why do we have to see it again?
- 为啥还要再看看啊？
The gentleman has a right
to see exhibits in evidence.
这位同志有权看看证物。
- Say, could you bring us the knife?
- 呃，你能拿一下那把刀吗？
- The knife? Sure.
- 那把刀？可以。
The knife and the way it was bought
is strong evidence, don't you think?
这把刀以及买刀的时间就是有力的证据，你说呢？
- I do.
- 没错。
- Good. Let's take the facts one at a time.
- 好，我们把事实逐条罗列出来。
One: The boy admitted leaving the house
at eight o'clock at night
一：被告人承认被他爸掌掴后
after being slapped by his father.
晚上8点离开房间。
No, he didn't say "slapped".
He said "punched". There's a difference.
错了，他没说“掌掴”，他说的是“拳打”。这是不一样的。
After being hit several times by his father.
在被他爸殴打几次之后。
Two: He went directly to a local junk shop
where he bought one of those...
二：他直接去旧货商店买了一把……
- Switch knives.
- 弹簧刀。
- Switchblade knives.
This wasn't an ordinary knife. It had
a very unusual carved handle and blade.
这不是普通的刀，它的刀柄和刀刃有很不寻常的雕刻.
The storekeeper said it was the only one
of its kind he had ever had in stock.
店主说这是他店里的唯一一把。
Three: He met some friends of his in front
of a tavern about 8.45. Am I right so far?
三：8：45左右他在一家酒馆门前和他的朋友碰面。我没说错吧？
- Yes, you are.
- 没错。
- You bet he is.
- 肯定没错。
He talked with his friends
for an hour, leaving them at 9.45.
他和他的朋友聊了一小时，9：45时离开。
During this time,
they saw the switch knife.
这期间，他们看到了这把弹簧刀。
Four: They identified the death weapon
in court as that very same knife.
四：他们确定法庭上的这把凶器正是那把弹簧刀。
Five: He arrived home
at about ten o'clock.
五：十点左右他回到家。
This is where the stories offered
by the State and the boy diverge slightly.
这里是检方版本与被告人版本有分歧的地方。
He claims that he went to a movie
at about 11.30,
被告人称他在11：30左右去了电影院，
returning home at 3.10 to find
his father dead and himself arrested.
3：10分回到家，发现他爸死了，接着就被逮捕了。
He also claims that the two detectives
threw him down a half a flight of stairs.
他还说两个侦查员把他仍下楼梯，滚了一段。
What happened to the knife? He claims
it fell through a hole in his pocket
弹簧刀哪去了呢？他说从他口袋的洞滑掉了。
on the way to the movies,
sometime between 11.30 and 3.10,
在去电影院的路上，11：30到3：10这段时间，
and that he never saw it again.
Now, there is a tale, gentlemen.
他没看到那把刀。注意了，同志们，这是谎言。
I think it's clear the boy
never went to the movies that night.
我认为当晚他压根就没去过什么电影院，这是明摆着的。
No one in the house saw him go out.
No one at the theatre identified him.
屋里的人没人看见他离开过。电影院的人也没人见过他。
He couldn't even remember
the names of the pictures he saw.
他甚至想不起他看过什么电影。
What actually happened is this.
其实事实应该是这样。
The boy stayed home,
had another fight with his father,
被告人呆在家里，又和他父亲打了一架，
stabbed him to death and left the house
at 10 minutes after 12.
捅死他父亲后在0：10离开家。
He even wiped the knife
clean of fingerprints.
他还把刀上的指纹抹掉了。
Are you trying to tell me that this knife
fell through a hole in the boy's pocket,
你想跟我说刀是从被告人口袋的洞口滑出来，
someone picked it up,
went to the boy's house
有人捡到它，然后到被告人家里
and stabbed his father with it
just to test its sharpness?
刺杀死者，以试一下刀锋吗？
No, but it's possible the boy lost his knife
不是的，但可能是被告人弄丢了弹簧刀
and somebody else stabbed his father
with a similar knife.
而有人用同样的刀捅死死者。
Take a look at this knife.
看看这把刀。
It's a very unusual knife.
这把刀很不一般。
I've never seen one like it. Neither had
the storekeeper who sold it to the boy.
我没见过类似的刀，卖刀的店主也没有。
Aren't you asking us to accept
an incredible coincidence?
难道你不是在要我们接受不可能的巧合吗？
- I'm just saying a coincidence is possible.
- 我只是说可能存在巧合。
- And I say it's not possible.
- 但我认为不可能存在这种巧合。
Where did that come from?
这刀是哪来的？
- It's the same knife!
- 一模一样啊！
- What do you think you're doin'?
- 你知道你这是在干嘛吗？
- Where did you get it?
- 你哪弄的刀？
- I went out walking last night.
- 昨晚我出去逛了逛。
Through the boy's neighbourhood.
通过被告人的邻居，
I bought that at a pawn shop two blocks
from the boy's house. It cost six dollars.
我在离被告人家两个街区的典当行买的，花了6美元。
It's against the law
to buy or sell switchblade knives.
买卖弹簧刀是犯法的。
- That's right. I broke the law.
- 没错，我违反了法律。
- You pulled a real bright trick.
- 你真会耍把戏啊。
Now supposing you tell me what it proves.
现在你说说这能证明什么。
- Maybe there are ten knives like that.
- 这样的刀可能有十把。
- Maybe there are!
- 可能真有！
-
What does it mean? You found a knife like
it. What's that? The discovery of the age?
这又说明什么？你找了把相同的刀，又证明什么呢？
时代的大发现吗？
You think somebody else did the stabbing
with exactly the same kind of knife?
你认为是别人用同样的刀行凶吗？
- The odds are a million to one.
- 可能性是微乎其微。
- It's possible!
- 有可能！
- But not very probable.
- 但不是很可能。
- OK, fellas. Let's take our seats.
- 好了，同志们，大家坐下。
There's no point standing around
all over the place.
大家随处站着就没个主题了。
It's interesting that he'd find a knife
exactly like the boy's.
他居然能找到和被告人很像的刀，有意思哈。
- What's interesting about it? Interesting!
- 这有什么意思？还有意思！
- I just thought it was interesting.
-我只是认为它很有意思。
Eleven of us still think he's guilty.
我们十一个人仍坚持认为他有罪。
Right. You're not gonna
change anybody's mind.
没错，你不可能改其他人的想法。
If you wanna hang this jury, go ahead.
如果你要耽搁大家，那就顺你的便吧。
The kid'll be tried again
and found guilty, as sure as he's born.
再重审一次，他也是被认定有罪，就像他已经来到世上一样确凿无疑。
You're probably right.
可能你是对的。
So, what are you gonna do?
We can be here all night.
那你打算怎么做？我们可以在这“枕戈待旦”。
It's only one night. A boy may die.
只有一晚上了，那小孩可能被处死。
Well, why don't we just
set up house here?
要不我们在这凑对过夜？
Someone send for a pinochle deck
谁去找来匹诺克（一种扑克牌游戏）
and we'll just sweat
the whole thing out right here.
然后我们在这把这个问题弄明白。
- I don't think he oughta joke about it.
- 我觉得他不是在开玩笑。
- What do you want me to do about it?
- 你要我干嘛？
I don't see what the knife
has got to do with anything.
我看不出这把刀能说明什么。
Somebody saw the kid stab his father.
What more do we need?
有人看见被告人捅死他的父亲，还要其他证据吗？
You guys can talk the ears
right off my head.
你们就唠叨个没完吧。
I got three garages going to pot.
So let's get done and get outta here.
我还有三个车库要整理，
我们快点弄完走人。
The knife was important to the
district attorney. He spent a day...
检察官认为这刀很重要，
他花了一天时间……
He's a 15th assistant or something.
What does he know?
他就是个无名小辈，他懂个屁啊！
Let's hold it down. These side arguments
are only slowin' us up.
别争了，再这么无谓地吵下去我们的进度就更慢了。
- Well, what about it?
- 那现在怎么办？
- You're the only one.
- 就你一个人反对。
I have a proposition to make to all of you.
I'm going to call for another vote.
我有个提议，大家再投一次票。
I want you eleven men to...
我希望你们十一个人……
vote by secret written ballot.
进行无记名投票。
I'll abstain. If there are eleven votes
for guilty, I won't stand alone.
我弃权，如果还是十一票认为有罪，那我就不再坚持。
We'll take in a guilty verdict
to the judge right now.
立马把有罪裁决提交给法官。
But if anyone votes not guilty,
we'll stay here and talk it out.
但如果有人投无罪票，那我们就继续讨论。
- That's it. If you want to try it, I'm ready.
- 就这样。如果你们同意，我没意见。
- All right. Let's do it the hard way.
- 好，就这么定了。
That sounds fair. Everyone agreed?
Anyone doesn't agree?
这样公平，大家都同意吧？有人反对吗？
OK, pass these along.
那好，我们来投票吧。
Guilty.
有罪。
Not guilty.
无罪。
Guilty.
有罪。
- Boy, how do you like that?
- 同志，你怎么能这样？
- And another chap flips his wings!
- 又一个脑子进水的！
All right. Who was it?
Come on, I wanna know.
好，谁投的票？快点，我要知道。
Excuse me. This was a secret ballot.
We all agreed on that, no?
抱歉，这是无记名投票，
我们都说好的，是不是？
If the gentleman
wants it to remain secret...
如果这位同志不想让别人知道……
Secret? What do you mean? There are no
secrets in a jury room. I know who it was.
不让别人知道？什么意思？陪审团里没有秘密。
我知道是谁了。
Brother, you really are somethin'.
You vote guilty like the rest of us,
同志，你真是神不知鬼不觉啊。
你和我们投有罪票，
then some golden-voiced preacher
tears your heart out -
然后被某人凭三寸不烂之舌说得晕头转向-
some underprivileged kid
couldn't help becoming a murderer -
被告人出身贫困，很容易行凶杀人-
and you change your vote.
If that isn't the most sickening...
你居然改变了立场。是可忍……
Why don't you drop a quarter
in his collection box?
你干嘛不投三个人的票呢？
（译似有误）
Oh, now just wait a... Listen, you can't talk
to me like that. Who do you think you are?
噢，等等……听着，你不能这么跟我说话。
你是哪根葱啊？
Calm down, calm down. It doesn't matter.
安静，安静，这没什么大不了的。
- He's very excitable. Sit down.
- 他很容易激动。坐下。
- Excitable? You bet I'm excitable!
- 容易激动？我TMD就是容易激动！
We're tryin' to put a guilty man
in the chair, where he belongs.
我们现在要把一个罪犯送上电椅，
他这是罪有应得。
Someone starts tellin' us
fairy tales and we're listenin'!
有人跟我们胡扯，而我们听得津津有味！
- What made you change your vote?
- 是什么让你改变了投票？
- He didn't change his vote. I did.
- 他没改变他的投票，是我改变了。
- Oh, fine.
- 哈，好啊。
- I knew it.
- 我就知道！
- Would you like me to tell you why?
- 你想知道为什么吗？
- No, I wouldn't like you to tell me why.
- 不想，我才不想听你的解释。
- I'd like to anyway, if you don't mind.
- 但我想解释一下，如果你不介意的话。
- Do we have to listen to this?
- 我们必须洗耳恭听吗？
- The man wants to talk.
- 这位同志想讨论一下。
- Thank you.
- 谢谢你。
This gentleman has been
standing alone against us.
这位同志一直孤军奋战。
He doesn't say the boy is not guilty.
他没有说被告无罪。
He just isn't sure. It's not easy to stand
alone against the ridicule of others.
他只是不确定。能够横眉冷对大家的冷嘲热讽、
孤军奋战，并不简单。
So he gambled for support and I gave it
to him. I respect his motives.
所以他孤注一掷、寻求支持，我支持他，
尊重他的动机。
The boy on trial is probably guilty,
but... I want to hear more.
被告人很可能有罪，但是……我想了解更多。
The vote is ten to two. I'm talking!
You have no right to leave this room!
投票结果是10：2.我在说，你不能离开这个房间！
He can't hear you. He never will.
Let's sit down.
他不会听你说的。他听不进去。我们坐下谈吧。
- Shall we continue?
- 我们要继续吗？
- Well, I think we ought to take a break.
- 嗯，我们先休息一下吧。
You know, one man's inside and
I think we ought to wait for him.
有一位同志在里面，我们要等他出来。
Looks like we're really
hung up here, huh?
看起来我们要困在这儿了？
I mean, that thing with the old man,
that was pretty unexpected.
我是说，那位老同志的举动，真是出人意料啊。
Wish I could figure out some way
we could break it up.
真希望我能想个办法，把这事给了结了。
You know, in advertising...
I told you I worked in an agency?
知道吗，在广告方面……
我跟你说过我在一个机构里干活吧？
Some pretty strange people work there.
Well, not strange, really.
在里面工作的有些很奇怪的人。
嗯，其实不奇怪。
I guess it's just they have peculiar ways
of expressing themselves.
我想只是他们有自己的方式表达自己。
I suppose it's the same
in your business too, huh?
我想在你的行业里也是一样的吧，哈？
- What do you do?
- 你是干嘛的？
- I'm a watchmaker.
- 我是做手表的。
Really? I imagine the finest watchmakers
in the world come from Europe.
真的？我想世界上最好的表匠是从欧洲来的吧？
Anyway, in an agency,
when we reach a point like this...
不管怎样，在代理行里，每当我们遇到这种情况……
I'm telling him, in an ad agency when
a point like this is reached in a meeting,
我跟他说，在广告代理行里，每当在会上碰到这种情况，
there's always some character
ready with an idea, see.
总有人想到点子。
It kills me. It's the weirdest thing,
让我佩服地五体投地啊。很诡异的是，
the way they sometimes precede
their idea with a phrase.
他们有时会通过俗语来表达想法。
Like, some account exec
will get up and he'll say:
比如，有的财务会站起来说：
"OK, here's an idea. Let's... run it up
the flagpole and see if anyone salutes it."
“好了，我有个办法。我们……把旗升起来，看有没有人敬礼。”
I mean, it's idiotic, but it's funny.
我是说，这很白痴，不过很搞。
I... got a little excited back there.
我……刚刚有点激动了。
I... didn't mean to get nasty.
我……不是要惹你生气。
Glad you're not one of those who lets
these emotional appeals influence him.
幸好你没有让这些情绪影响他。
I don't know what's the matter
with that fan.
不知这风扇出了什么毛病。
- Are you a salesman?
- 你是做推销的吗？
- I'm an architect.
- 我是搞建筑的。
You know what the soft sell is?
你知道什么叫软推销吗？
Well, you've got it, believe me.
哼，相信我，你做的就是。
I've got a different technique.
我的方法就不一样了。
Laughs, drinks, jokes, tricks. You know?
大笑、喝酒、开玩笑、耍花招。懂吗？
Yeah.
嗯。
Hit 'em where they live-that's my motto.
挠其痒处――这是我的座右铭。
I made 27 grand last year
sellin' marmalade.
去年卖果酱，我赚了二万七。
That's not bad. I mean, you know,
considerin' marmalade.
这成绩不错了。你想想卖的是果酱啊。
What are you gettin' out of this? Kicks?
你能从中得到什么好处呢？挨踢吗？
Or did somebody bump you on the head
once and you haven't gotten over it?
还是有人把你脑袋撞坏了，你还恢复过来？
- Maybe.
- 或许吧。
- You know, you do-gooders are all alike.
- 你们这些老好人都一副丑德性。
You're always blowin' your stacks
over some guy that fanned.
总是爱火上浇油。
But what are you wastin' our time for?
不过你干嘛要浪费大家的时间呢？
Why don't you donate five dollars to the
cause? Maybe it'll make you feel better.
你干嘛不捐个四五块钱行个善，也许这会让你好受些。
This kid is guilty, pal.
这小孩有罪，同志。
It's as plain as the nose on your face. So
why don't we stop wastin' our time here?
就像你脸上的鼻子一样，明摆着的。你干嘛非得浪费大伙儿的时间呢？
We're gonna all get sore throats
if we keep it up.
再这样下去，我们嗓子都冒烟了。
What difference does it make
if you get it here or at the ball game?
你呆在这跟你去看球赛有啥区别吗？
No difference, pal.
没啥区别，同志。
No difference at all.
没一点儿区别。
- Nice bunch of guys, huh?
- 真是一群难缠的家伙，哈？
- They're about the same as anyone else.
- 他们和其他人一个样。
Boy, what a murderous day.
同志，今天真是度日如年啊。
- Do you think we'll be much longer?
- 你觉得我们还要接着熬吗？
- I don't know.
- 我不清楚。
He's guilty for sure.
Not a doubt in the whole world.
那小子是罪证确凿，是毫无疑问的。
We should've...
We should've been done already.
我们本应……
我们本应早早收场了。
Oh, I don't mind, you know.
噢，其实我不介意。
Beats workin'.
慢工出细活嘛。
- You think he's not guilty, huh?
- 你认为他是无辜的，啊？
- I don't know. It's possible.
- 我不知道，有可能。
Well, I don't know you, but I'm bettin'
you've never been wronger in your life.
呃，我对你不了解，不过我敢说这是你一生最大的错误了。
You're wastin' your time.
You ought to wrap it up.
你是在浪费你的时间。你应该鸣金收兵了。
Supposing you were the one
who was on trial?
假设被审判的人是你？
Well, I'm not used to supposin'.
I'm just a workin' man.
呃，我不做假设，我身体力行。
My boss does the supposin'. But...
我老板才做假设。但是……
I'll try one.
我尝试假设一下。
Supposin' you talk us all out of this and...
假设你把我们都说服了，而……
the kid really did knife his father, huh?
被告人真的杀害了他的父亲，哈？
Are you ready?
准备好了？
Sorry, blue eyes.
抱歉，蓝眼睛。
- Well, where else?
- 呃，其他人呢？
- OK, fellas. Let's take our seats.
- 好了，同志们，大家坐下。
- Looks like we'll be here for dinner.
- 看来我们要在这吃晚饭了。
- OK, now let's get down to business.
- 好了，我们讨论正事吧。
- Who wants to start?
- 谁想发言？
- I will.
- 我想。
- OK, go.
- 好，说吧。
- You, down there.
- 就你，坐那儿的。
The old man who lived downstairs says
he heard the kid yell "I'm gonna kill ya."
住楼下的那老头说他听到被告人大喊“我要杀了你。”
A second later,
he heard the body hit the floor.
不一会儿，他听到身体撞到地板的声音。
He ran to the door and saw the kid run out
of the house. What's that mean to you?
他跑到门口，看见被告人跑出房间。你对这怎么看？
I wonder how clearly he heard
the boy's voice through the ceiling.
我纳闷透过天花板，他能听清被告人的声音吗。
He didn't. The window was open. So was
the one upstairs. It was a hot night.
不是天花板，窗户是开着的。楼上的窗户也是开着的。
那晚很热。
It was another apartment.
It's not easy to identify a shouting voice.
Particularily a shouting voice.
那是另一个房间，很难确定谁在叫喊。
特别是叫喊声。
He identified it in court.
他在法庭上确认了。
The lady across the street looked right in
the open window and saw the stabbing.
街对过的妇女通过开着的窗户正好看见行凶的过程。
- Isn't that enough for you?
- 这还不够吗？
- No, it isn't
- 不行，不够。.
Boy, how do you like this guy?
It's like talkin' into a dead phone.
同志，你跟他费什么劲儿啊？
简直是对牛弹琴。
She said she saw it through
the windows of a moving el train.
她说她从经过的轻轨的窗户看见的。
There were six cars on the train.
She saw it through the last two.
那列轻轨有6节车厢，她是从后2个车厢看到的。
She remembered insignificant details.
How can you argue with that?
她连细枝末节都记得，你还有什么可说的？
Has anybody here any idea
how long it would take an el...
你们谁知道一列轻轨要多长时间……
This isn't a game.
这不是儿戏！
Did you see him?
你们看到了嘛？
The nerve! The absolute nerve!
神经质！太神经了！
- Forget it. It's not important.
- 算了，没什么大不了的。
- This isn't a game?
- 这不是个游戏吗？
- Who does he think he is?
- 他以为他是哪根葱啊？
- Forget it now.
- 算了吧。
Any idea how long it takes an el train
at medium speed to pass a given point?
谁知道一列轻轨以中等速度通过一个点要多长时间？
- What has that to do with it?
- 这有关系吗？
- Guess.
- 想想。
- I wouldn't have any idea.
- 我不清楚。
- What do you think?
- 你要干嘛？
- I don't know. Ten, twelve seconds?
- 我不知道。10秒，12秒？
- A pretty good guess. Anyone else?
- 很好。其他人呢？
- Sounds right to me.
- 我觉得差不多。
- What's the guessing game for?
- 猜什么灯谜啊？
- What do you say?
- 你怎么看？
- Ten seconds.
- 10秒。
- All right. What are you getting at?
- 好了，你要干嘛？
- This.
- 这个。
It takes a six-car el train
ten seconds to pass a given point.
6节车厢的轻轨经过一个点要10秒钟。
Say the given point is the open window
of the room where the killing took place.
假设这个点是案发房间开着的窗户。
You can reach out
and almost touch the el tracks, right?
你伸手差不多可以碰到轻轨，对吧？
Now let me ask you this. Has anyone
here ever lived near the el tracks?
现在我问你们。你们有谁住在轻轨附近？
I just finished painting an apartment that
overlooked an el line. It took three days.
我刚装修完可以看到轻轨的套间。花了三天时间。
- What was it like? Noisy?
- 是什么样的情况？很吵？
- Oh, brother! No matter. We were punchy.
- 同志啊，其他还好，我们脑袋都快要炸了。
I lived in an apartment
near the el line once.
我以前住在轻轨附近。
When the window's open,
the train noise is almost unbearable.
开窗的话，轻轨的声响让人无法忍受。
- You can hardly hear yourself think.
- 你都听不清你自己说什么。
- Will you get to the point?
- 你能直奔主题吗？
I will. Now, let's take two pieces of
testimony and try to put them together.
别急。我们把两份证词放一块儿，看看能不能吻合。
First: The old man
in the apartment downstairs.
第一：楼下的老头。
He says he heard the boy say
"I'm gonna kill you",
他说他听见被告人说“我要杀了你”，
and a split second later
heard a body hit the floor.
不一会儿就听到身体撞到地板上。
- One second later.
- 一秒钟后。
- That's right.
- 没错。
Second: The woman across the street
第二：街对过的女人
swore positively she looked
out of the window and saw the killing
发誓她从窗户看到了杀人过过程
through the last two cars
of a passing el train-the last two cars.
透过轻轨的后两节车厢――后两节。
- What are you givin' us here?
- 你要跟我们说什么？
- Now, just a minute.
- 稍等一下。
We've agreed that it takes ten seconds
for a train to pass a given point.
我们刚说了一列轻轨经过一个点要10秒钟。
Since the woman saw the killing
through the last two cars,
如果那女的从后两节车厢看到杀人，
we can assume that the body hit
the floor just as the train went by.
我们可以推断尸体落地时正好是轻轨经过。
Therefore, the train had been
roaring by the old man's window
因此，轻轨呼啸经过老头的窗户
a full ten seconds
before the body hit the floor.
足有10秒钟，在尸体落地之前。
The old man - "I'm gonna kill you",
body hitting the floor a second later -
老头――“我要杀了你”，一秒钟后身体落地――
would have had to hear the boy's words
with the el roaring past his nose!
老头能从身边呼啸经过的轻轨声中听出被告人说的话吗？
- It's not possible he heard it.
- 他不可能听得到。
- Of course he heard it.
- 他当然听到了。
- Do you think so?
- 你真这么看？
- He said he yelled at the top of his voice.
- 他说了他是扯破了嗓子喊的。
He couldn't have identified the voice
with the el roaring by.
他不可能从呼啸经过的轻轨声中听到说话的。
It was a matter of seconds!
Nobody can be that accurate.
只是几秒钟的事，没人能说得很精确。
Testimony that could put a boy into the
electric chair shou/d be that accurate.
能把被告人送上电椅的证词就得要说得很精确。
- I don't think he could have heard it.
- 我不觉得他能听得到。
- Maybe he didn't, with all that el noise.
- 可能他听不到，因为轻轨的噪音。
- What are you people talkin' about?
- 你们在胡说什么呀？
- It stands to reason he couldn't have.
- 逻辑上讲，他是不可能听得见的。
- Why lie? What's he got to gain?
- 为啥要撒谎？他能得到什么好处吗？
- Attention, maybe.
- 关注吧，可能。
You keep comin' in with bright sayings.
Send 'em to a paper! They pay $3 apiece!
你插嘴时候总是满口哲理啊。
寄给报社吧，每件3块钱呢！
What are you talkin' to him like that for?
你那么蛮横对他想干嘛？
A guy who talks like that to an old man
really oughta get stepped on.
这样对待这位老人应该受谴责。
You oughta have more respect, mister.
你要表示一点尊重，同志。
You say stuff like that to him again...
I'm gonna lay you out.
你要是还那样跟他说话……
我就让你出局。
You go ahead. You say anything you like.
请你继续，把你想说的说完。
Why do you think the old man might lie?
为什么你认为那老人会撒谎？
It was just that I looked at him
for a very long time.
我观察他好长时间了。
The seam of his jacket was split,
under the shoulder.
他的夹克都裂缝了，肩下的地方。
Did you notice that?
I mean, to come into court like that.
你注意到了吗？我是说，这样穿着出庭。
He was a very old man in a torn jacket.
他年纪很大、衣衫褴褛。
And he walked very slowly to the stand.
他走向证人席的时候走得非常慢。
He was dragging his left leg
and trying to hide it,
拖着左腿，却试图隐藏，
because he was ashamed.
因为他觉得不好意思。
I think I know this man
better than anyone here.
我觉得我比在座的各位更了解他。
This is a quiet, frightened,
这是个沉默寡言、如惊弓之鸟、
insignificant old man who...
又被人忽略的老人，他……
who has been nothing all his life.
他一生被弃如敝屣。
Who has never had recognition
or his name in the newspapers.
从未被认同、也从未被关注过。
Nobody knows him. Nobody quotes him.
没人知道他，没人提起他。
Nobody seeks his advice after 75 years.
75年来没人要问问他的意见。
Gentlemen, that's a very sad thing -
to mean nothing.
同志们，这是很惨的――什么也不是。
A man like this needs to be quoted,
to be listened to.
想像这样的人需要被人提起、被人聆听。
To be quoted just once -
very important to him.
哪怕就一回――对他而言也很重要。
It would be so hard for him
to recede into the background.
要他继续默默无闻，很困难。
Wait a minute. Are you tellin' us he'd lie
just so he could be important once?
等等。你说他撒谎就为了受人重视一次？
No. He wouldn't really lie.
不是，他可能没撒谎。
But perhaps he made himself believe
he heard those words
但是他可能认为自己听到了叫喊
and recognised the boy's face.
并且看到被告人的脸。
That's the most fantastic story ever.
这真是天方夜谭。
How can you make up a thing like that?
What do you know about it?
你怎么能捏造这种事情？
你是怎么知道的？
- Does anybody want a cough drop?
- 谁要止咳糖？
- I'll take one.
- 我来一颗。
I still don't see how anybody
can think he's not guilty.
我还是想不通大家怎么认为他是无罪的。
There's something else I'd like
to talk about for a minute. Thanks.
还有其他的，我想花一分钟说一下。谢谢。
We've proved the old man couldn't have
heard the boy say "I'm gonna kill you."
我们刚刚证明了那老人不可能听到被告人喊
“我要杀了你”。
- You didn't prove it at all!
- 你压根就没证明！
- Wait. Supposing he really did hear it?
- 等等，如果他真的听到了呢？
This phrase, how many times have
all of us used it? Probably thousands.
这种话我们说了多少遍了？数千遍了吧。
"I could kill you for that." "Junior, do that
again and I'll kill you." "Rocky, kill him."
“我要弄死你。”“小子，再这样我就弄死你。”
“Rocky,干死他。”
- It doesn't mean we'd really kill anybody.
- 这不是说我们真的要杀掉某人。
- The phrase was: "I'm gonna kill you."
- 他说的是：“我要杀了你。”
The kid yelled it at the top of his lungs.
被告人是歇斯底里。
Don't tell me he didn't mean it.
Anybody says it like that, they mean it!
别跟我说他不是这么想。
所有人这么说，就都是这个意思！
Gee, I don't know.
呵，我不这么看。
I was arguing with the guy I work next to
at the bank a few weeks ago.
几个星期前，我在银行和同我一块儿干活的家伙吵了一架。
He called me an idiot, so I yelled at him.
他说我是白痴，我就对他吼。
This guy is trying to make you
believe what isn't so!
这家伙是要让你们认为不是这么回事儿！
The kid said he'd kill him and he did!
被告人说他要杀了他，就把他杀了。
Do you really think the boy'd shout it out
so the whole neighbourhood could hear?
你真的认为被告人大喊大叫，为了让邻居都听到吗？
- He's much too bright for that.
- 他诡计多端。
- Bright? He's a common, ignorant slob.
- 诡计多端？他只不过是个普通、愚昧的笨蛋。
He don't even speak good English.
他连英语都说不好。(注意don't ^_^)
He doesn't even speak good English.
是他连英语都说不好。
Mr Foreman, I'd like to
change my vote to not guilty.
组长同志，我想改投无罪票。
- You what?
- 什么？
- You heard me.
- 你没听见吗？
- Are you sure?
- 你确定？
- Yeah, I'm sure.
- 是的，我确定。
The vote is nine to three
in favour of guilty.
9票有罪，3票无罪。
Well, if this isn't the livin' end!
哈，简直要没完没了了。
What are you basin' it on?
Stories this guy made up?
你的根据是什么？这家伙的扯淡吗？
You oughta write for one of those kooky
detective magazines, make a fortune.
你应该给那些侦探杂志写专栏，会让你暴富的。
For cryin' out loud, the kid's own lawyer
knew he didn't stand a chance.
除了咆哮，被告人的律师就知道他没有一丁点儿胜算。
Right from the beginning, his own
lawyer knew, and you could see it.
从一开始，他的律师就一清二楚，你也看到了。
Boy, oh boy, I'm telling ya.
This guy here is really somethin'.
同志啊同志，我就跟你说过，这家伙不是省油的灯。
The kid had a lawyer, didn't he?
He presented his case, not you.
被告人有律师，没有吗？
是他代理案件，不是你。
- How come you say so much?
- 你哪来那么多废话？
- Lawyers aren't infallible.
- 律师也有马失前蹄的时候。
- Baltimore, please.
- 巴尔的摩队的。(讥笑他和巴队一样菜^_^)
- He was court-appointed.
- 他是法庭指定的。
- What's that supposed to mean?
- 那又说明什么？
- A lot.
- 多了。
He didn't want the case
or he resented being appointed.
他不想接这个案子或者他反对指定。
It's the kind of case that brings no money,
no glory, not much chance of winning.
这类案子没钱可赚，又不光鲜，胜算又小。
That's not a very promising
situation for a young lawyer.
对年轻律师而言，没什么前途。
He'd really have to believe in his client to
put up a good case. Obviously he didn't.
他本应信任他的当事人，好好辩护。显然他没有。
Of course he didn't.
他当然没有了。
Who the heck could?
谁会啊？
Except maybe some guy's mother
or somebody.
除了他娘或是某些人。
Oh, look.
Will you look at the time? Come on.
噢，看看。你看看时间，快点儿吧。
Pardon me. I have made some notes here,
我讲几句。我做了些笔记，
and I would like, please,
to say something.
我想想说说我的看法。
I have been listening very carefully and...
我一直听得很仔细，
it seems to me that this man
has some very good points to make.
我觉得这位同志有些说的挺有道理。
From what was presented at the trial,
the boy looks guilty, on the surface.
从法庭上呈报的证据来看，表面上被告人有罪。
- But maybe if we go deeper...
- 但如果我们深入地……
- Come on, will ya?
- 能快点儿吗？
There is a question I would like to ask.
我想问个问题。
Let us assume that the boy
really did commit the murder.
我们假设被告人实施了犯罪行为。
Now, this happened
at 10 minutes after 12.
这发生在0：12.
Now, how was he caught by the police?
嗯，那他怎么被警察逮到的呢？
He came back home...
at three o'clock or so,
他回了一趟家……在3点左右，
and he was captured by two detectives
in the hallway of his house.
在他家的过道被两名侦查员逮个正着。
Now, my question is:
If he really had killed his father,
那我的问题是：如果他真的杀害了他的父亲，
why would he come back home
three hours later?
他为何还要在3小时后回家？
Wouldn't he be afraid of being caught?
难道他不怕被抓吗？
He came home for his knife. It's not nice
to leave knives in people's chests.
他回家是为了那把刀。把刀留在别人胸口可不是什么好事。
Yeah, especially relatives'.
是，尤其是自己人。
I don't see anything funny about it.
我不觉得这有什么好笑的。
The boy knew the knife
could be identified.
被告人知道那把刀会被认出来的。
- He had to get it before the police did.
- 他要在警察前面把刀拿走。
- If he knew the knife could be identified,
- 如果他知道刀会被认出来，
why did he leave it there in the first place?
那他为啥一开始就把刀落下？
I think we can assume the boy ran out in a
state of panic, having just killed his father.
我觉得我们可以假设被告人杀害他爸后，心里很是慌张。
He calmed down and realised
he'd left his knife there.
他冷静下来后就意识到他把刀落下了。
This, then, depends
on your definition of panic.
这就得看你怎么定义慌张了。
He would have had to be calm enough to
wipe off any fingerprints left on the knife.
他本应冷静地把刀上的指纹抹掉。
Now, where did this panic start
and where did it end?
那他的慌张是什么时候开始，什么时候停止的呢？
You voted guilty. What side are you on?
你投的是有罪票，你到底站在哪边？
I don't believe I have to be loyal
to one side or the other.
我不觉得我有义务忠于哪一方。
- I'm simply asking questions.
- 我只是提出疑问。
- This is just off the top of my head but...
- 这是我刚想到的，但是……
If /'d done the stabbing, I'd take a chance
and go back for the knife.
如果是我杀的人，我会冒险回去把刀找到。
I'll bet he figured
nobody'd seen him running out
我敢说他是认为没人看到他跑出去
and the body wouldn't be discovered
till the next day.
尸体在第二天才会被发现。
After all, it was the middle of the night.
He figured it'd be found the next day.
总之，那时已经是午夜了。他认为第二天才会被发现。
Pardon. This is my whole point.
等等，这就是我要说的。
The woman across the street testified
that the moment after she saw the killing,
街对过的女人作证说她看到杀人后，
that is, a moment after the train went by,
也就是轻轨经过之后，
she screamed, and then went
to telephone the police.
她失声尖叫，然后报了警。
Now, the boy certainly
must have heard the scream.
那被告人肯定能够听到尖叫。
So he knew that
somebody saw something.
那他就知道有人看到了。
I just don't think
that he would have gone back.
我认为他不会返回家。
Two things. One: He may not have heard
the scream. Perhaps it wasn't very loud.
二种可能。一：他没听到尖叫。可能是因为声音不大。
Two: If he did, he may not
have connected it with his own acts.
二：如果他听到了，他没把它和他的行为联系起来。
He lived in a neighbourhood
where screams were commonplace.
他住的地方经常有人大喊大叫。
- There's your answer.
- 那是你这么认为。
- Maybe. Maybe the boy did kill his father.
- 也许吧。也许被告人确实杀害了他的父亲。
Didn't hear the scream,
did run out in a panic,
没听到尖叫，慌张出逃，
calmed down later and came back for the
knife, risking being caught by the police.
冷静下来后返回找刀，冒着被警察抓捕的风险。
Maybe those things happened,
but maybe they didn't.
可能是这样，也可能不是这样子。
There's enough doubt to wonder if he was
there at all at the time of the killing.
案发当时他是否在场，疑窦很多。
What do you mean? Didn't the old man
see him running out of the house?
你什么意思啊？难道老头没看见他跑出房间吗？
He's twisting the facts.
他这是歪曲事实。
Did or didn't the old man see the kid
running out of the house at 12.10?
老人有没有看到被告人在0：12跑出房间呢？
- Well, did or didn't he?
- 他到底有没有呢？
- He says he did.
- 他说他看见了。
Says he did? Boy, how do you like that?
他说他看到了？同志，你怎能这样？
- Witnesses can make mistakes.
- 证人也有可能犯错。
- Sure, when you want them to!
- 当然，你想他们犯错的时候！
- Or when he wants them to!
- 或是他想他们犯错！
- Keep the yelling down.
- 嗓门别那么大。
Maybe we need a little yelling. These
guys keep going off every which way.
可能我们要嗓门大一点儿。这帮人算尽各种假设。
Did hear the scream, didn't hear it -
what difference does it make?
听到尖叫，没听到尖叫――这有什么区别吗？
You're talking about little details
and forgetting the important stuff.
你们只注意鸡毛蒜皮，却忽略关键所在。
- I call for another vote.
- 我提议再投一次票。
- I'm talking here!
- 我在说呢！
Another vote called for.
有人要求再投一次。
Now let's take our seats.
我们回到自己的位子。
I never saw so much time
spent on nothin'.
我没见过这么没事找事的。
It only takes a second.
只要几秒钟。
OK, I guess the fastest way is
to find out who's voting not guilty.
好了，我觉得最简便的方法是看谁投无罪票。
All those voting not guilty,
please raise your hands.
投无罪票的，请举手。
Still the same. One, two, three
not guilty. Nine guilty.
还是一样。1、2、3票无罪，9票有罪。
So now where are we? We can yakety-yak
till next Tuesday. Where's it getting us?
那我们怎么办？我们可以一直吵到星期二，这有何益处？
Pardon. I vote not guilty.
抱歉，我投无罪票。
What are you talkin' about? I mean,
we're all goin' crazy in here or somethin'.
你说啥？我们在这儿会发疯的。
The kid is guilty.
Why don't you listen to the facts?
被告人有罪。你为啥不看看事实？
Tell them, will ya?
This is gettin' to be a joke.
你跟他们说说。这是天大的笑话。
The vote is eight to four in favour of guilty.
现在是8票有罪，4票无罪。
What is this?
Love Your Underprivileged Brother Week?
这是干嘛？怜悯难兄难弟周吗？
I want you to tell me why
you changed your vote. Give me reasons.
我希望你能说说你为啥要改变主意。说说理由。
I don't have to defend my decision to you.
There is a reasonable doubt in my mind.
我没必要跟你争辩我的决定。我有合理怀疑。
Reasonable doubt?
Nothing but words. Look at this.
合理怀疑？一堆说辞。看看这个。
The kid you just decided isn't guilty
was seen ramming this into his father!
你刚刚认为无罪的被告的用这个捅死他的父亲！
- What about this, Mr Reasonable Doubt?
- 怎么解释这个，合理怀疑同志？
- That's not the knife, remember?
- 不是这把刀，忘了吗？
- Oh, brilliant!
- 噢，反应真快！
- I'm tellin' you, this is the craziest.
- 我告诉你，没见过比这疯狂的。
I mean, what are we supposed to believe?
You're pullin' stories out of thin air.
我们应该相信什么？你这是凭空捏造。
A guy like this, if he's sittin' ringside
at the Dempsey-Firpo fight,
像这样的家伙，要是他坐在Dempsey对Pirpo比赛的场边
（著名的一场拳击比赛）
he'd be trying to tell you that...
他会告诉你的……
Look. Now what about the old man?
听着，那位老头呢？
Are we supposed to believe he didn't
see the kid tearin' down the steps
我们要相信他没看见被告的跑下楼梯
15 seconds after the killing?
在杀人后的15秒
He's just sayin' so to be important, right?
他这么说只是为要了引人注目，是吗？
- What's the point of it all?
- 这么说有啥意义？
- Hold it.
-等等。
The Baltimore rooter is heard from again.
巴队猪又开始嗷嗷叫了。
- And pop-ups are fallin' for base hits.
- 安打，鸣枪。（意指不想跟他吵）
- Hold on a second. Look.
- 等待，听着。
- Did the old man say he ran to the door?
- 那老人说过他跑到门口了吗？
- What's the difference?
- 有区别吗？
- He got there, didn't he?
- 他到门口了，是吗？
- He said he ran. At least I think he did.
- 他说他跑了，至少我认为他跑了。
I don't remember, but I don't see
how he could have run.
我忘了，不过我看不出他能跑。
He said he went from his bedroom
to the front door. Isn't that enough?
他说他从卧室走到前门。这行了吧？
- Where was the bedroom?
- 卧室在哪？
- Down the hall.
- 楼道尽头。
- Don't you remember that?
- 你忘了吗？
- No.
- 没有。
- I want to see a diagram of the apartment.
- 我想看看那个房间的构图。
- Why don't we have him on trial again?
- 我们干嘛不重新再审他一次呢？
You're the only one
wants to see exhibits.
就你一个人想看看证物。
- I want to see this one, too.
- 我也想看看。
- I'd like to stop wastin' time.
- 我希望不要浪费时间。
If we're gonna wade through
that nonsense about the body...
如果我们要纠缠于关于尸体的废话……
No, but I'd like to know if an old man
who drags one foot cos he had a stroke
不是，但我想知道一个中风的老人，拖着半条腿
can get from his bedroom
to his front door in 15 seconds.
怎么做到在15秒钟内从卧室走到前门的。
- He said 20.
- 他说的是20秒。
- He said 15.
- 他说的是15秒。
- 20. What are you tryin' to distort?
- 20秒。你要歪曲什么啊？
- He said 15.
- 他说的是15秒。
How does he know how long
15 seconds is? You can't judge that.
他怎么知道15秒钟有多久？这种事你能判断吗？
He said 15. He was positive about it.
他说了15秒。他很肯定。
He was an old man! He was confused!
他是个老头啊！老糊涂了！
How could he be positive about anything?
他怎么肯定？
I don't see what you're going to prove.
The man said he saw the boy running out.
我不会看你要证明什么。老头说了他亲眼看见被告的逃跑。
Let's see if the details bear him out.
As the body hit the floor,
我们看看事实能不能印证。当尸体落地，
he said he heard footsteps upstairs,
running to the front door.
他说他听到楼上脚步声，跑向前门。
Heard the upstairs door open,
the footsteps start down.
听见楼上的门打开，下楼的声音。
He said he got to his own door in, at most,
15 seconds. If the killer ran immediately...
他说他走到他的门口，差不多15秒。如果凶手立即逃跑……
- Maybe he didn't.
- 可能他没有。
- The old man said he did.
- 老头说了他是。
You oughta be at
that hair-splitters' convention.
你应该参加钻牛角尖大会。
Why don't you stop
making smart remarks?
你就不能不发表一下你的高见？
My friend, for your three dollars a day,
you have to listen to everything.
同志啊，就为了一天三块钱，你什么都得听。
Here's the apartment where the killing
took place. The old man's was
directly beneath and exactly the same.
这是案发房间。老人的房间在正下方，结构一样。
Here are the el tracks, the bedroom, living
room, kitchen, bathroom, hall, stairs.
这是轻轨、卧室、客厅、厨房、卫生间、楼道、楼梯。
The old man was in this bedroom here.
当时老人是在这个卧室。
He says he crossed to the door,
walked down the hall, opened the door
他说他穿过门，经过楼道，开门
just in time to see the boy
running down the stairs. Am I right?
正好看见被告人从楼上跑下来。我说的没错吧？
That's the story, for the 19th time.
是这样，第19遍了。
- 15 seconds after the body hit the floor.
- 尸体落地15秒后。
- Correct.
- 对的。
Now, let's see. It was...
我们来看，这是……
It's 12 feet from the bed to the door.
The hall is 43 feet.
床到门的距离是12英尺，楼道是43英尺。
He would have had to walk 12 feet,
open the bedroom door,
他要走12英尺，打开卧室的门，
walk 43 feet down and open
the front door, all in 15 seconds.
走43英尺，再开前门，一共15秒。
- Could he have done it?
- 他做得到吗？
- Sure.
- 当然了。
He walks slowly. He needed help
into the witness chair.
他走得很慢，走上证人席还要搀扶。
- You make it sound like a long walk.
- 你说起来好像走了十万八千里。
- For an old man who had a stroke, it is.
- 对一个中了见的老人，就这样子。
- What are you doin'?
- 你这是要干嘛？
- I'm gonna try it.
- 我试试。
What do you mean?
Why didn't his lawyer bring it up?
你什么意思？他的律师干嘛不提出来？
- Maybe he just didn't think of it.
- 可能他没想到吧。
- Do you think he's an idiot? It's obvious.
- 你以为他是个白痴啊？这一目了然啊。
- Did you think of it?
- 你想到了吗？
- It doesn't matter. He didn't bring it up
- 这不重要。反正律师没提出
because he knew it'd hurt his case.
因为他知道这对案子没帮助。
Or because it would have meant bullying
and badgering a helpless old man.
或者因为那会惊扰一个无助的老人。
That doesn't sit well with a jury.
Most lawyers avoid it if they can.
那对陪审团不起作用。如果可以，很多律师会省掉。
- What kind of a bum is he?
- 那还要他干嘛用？
- That's what I'm asking.
- 这是我要问的。
Pass me that chair.
Those two chairs are the old man's bed.
把那椅子递给我。那两张椅子是老人的床。
I just paced off 12 feet.
This is the bedroom door.
我刚用脚量了12英尺。这是卧室门。
That's crazy.
You can't re-create a thing like that.
太荒唐了。你没法再现现场。
The hall was 43 feet.
I'll pace from that wall and back again.
楼道是43英尺。我用脚量到墙再量回来。
This is insane. What are you
wasting everybody's time for?
神经病啊，你干嘛浪费大家的时间？
According to you, it'll only take
15 seconds. We can spare that.
按你说的，只要15秒钟。这点儿时间我们还是有的。
Come on. Knock it off.
拜托，不要吹了。
OK. OK, OK, killer.
好，好，好，凶手。
Yeah.
好。
Will you stand there and mark the front
door? It was chain-locked, remember.
你能站这儿作一前门吗？这是用链锁上的，记得啊。
- Who's got a watch with a second hand?
- 谁有带秒针的表？
- I have.
- 我有。
Stamp your foot. That'll be the body
falling. You can time me from there.
跺一下脚，这是尸体落地，这时你可以开始计时了。
- What are we gonna do, play charades?
- 我们要干嘛，过家家吗？
- What are we waiting for?
- 我们还等什么？
I wanna wait till
the second hand reaches 60.
我在等秒针走到60.
Aw, come on!
噢，快点儿了！
Come on, speed it up.
He can walk twice as fast as that.
拜托，走快点儿。你走一步他走两步了。
If you want me to walk
faster than that, I will.
你要我走快点儿，那我就快点儿。
- Lock. Door. Stop.
- 开锁、开门、停。
- Right.
- 好。
What's the time?
多长时间？
Exactly... 41 seconds.
准确地说是……41秒。
This is what I think happened. The old
man heard the fight a few hours earlier.
我认为事实是这样的。数小时前老人听到打架。
When he's in bed,
he heard the body hit the floor,
他躺床上的时候，听到尸体落地，
heard the woman scream, got to
his front door as fast as he could,
听见女人尖叫，尽可能快地走到前门，
heard somebody running
and assumed it was the boy.
听到有人在跑，认为那人就是被告人。
- I think that's possible.
- 我认为这有可能。
- Assumed?
- 假设？
Brother, I've seen all kinds
of dishonesty in my day,
同志，我看了一天的谎言，
but this little display takes the cake.
但最大的谎言要数这个小把戏了。
You all come in here with your hearts
bleedin' about slum kids and injustice.
你们到这来，为这穷小子怜惜，为不正义哀叹。
You listen to some fairy tales. You start
getting through to these old ladies.
你们听他讲童话。你可以愚弄他们。
You're not getting through to me.
I've had enough.
你不可能愚弄我。我受够了。
What's the matter with you guys?
You all know he's guilty! He's got to burn!
你们这帮人到底怎么了？你们都知道他有罪！
他就该被烧死！
- He'll slip through our fingers.
- 他就从我们的手里溜掉了。
- Slip through our fingers?
- 从我们手里溜掉？
- Are you his executioner?
- 你是执刑者之一？
- I'm one of 'em.
- 我是其中一个。
- Perhaps you'd like to pull the switch.
- 可能你是想拉那个电闸吧。
- For this kid, you bet I would.
- 给这小子，你说得没错。
I feel sorry for you. What it must
feel like to wanna pull the switch!
我为你感到悲哀。去拉那个闸会是什么感受！
Ever since you walked in, you've acted
like a self-appointed public avenger.
打你进来，你就是自封的公众复仇人。
You want to see this boy die because
you want it, not because of the facts.
你希望看这小孩死是因为你希望，而不是因为事实如此。
- You're a sadist.
- 你真是施虐狂啊。
- You...
- 你……
Let me go! I'll kill him! I'll kill him!
放开我！我弄死他！我弄死他！
You don't really mean
you'll kill me, do you?
你不会打算把我杀掉吧，会吗？
- Anything wrong? I heard some noise.
- 出什么事了吗？我听见吵闹了。
- No, everything's all right.
- 没有，一切正常。
We're just... Friendly little argument.
我们只是……友好讨论。
We're through with that diagram.
You can take it if you want. Here you are.
我们不需要这个结构图了。你可以拿走了。给你。
What are you lookin' at?
有啥好看的？
- Somebody has to start off again.
- 得有人再起个头了。
- I beg pardon...
- 请原谅……
"I beg pardon."
What are you so polite about?
“请原谅”你干嘛这么礼貌？
For the same reason you're not.
It's the way I was brought up.
和你不礼貌的原因一个样。我从小就这样。
This fighting... That's not
why we are here, to fight.
吵架……我们来这不是为了吵架。
We have a responsibility.
我们是有任务的。
This, I have always thought,
is a remarkable thing about democracy.
我一直认为这对民主而言非常重要。
That we are...
我们是……
What is the word?
这话怎么说了？
Notified. That we are notified by mail
to come down to this place
通知。我们被通知来到这里
to decide on the guilt or innocence of a
man we... we have never heard of before.
来决定被告人有罪还是无罪……这人我们从未听说过。
We have nothing to gain or lose
by... by our verdict.
我们的裁决不会让我得到什么、失去什么。
This is one of the reasons
why we are strong.
这就是为什么我们很强大的原因。
We should not make it a... personal thing.
我们不应该把他变成个人之间的恩怨。
If nobody else has an idea,
I might have a cutie here.
如果有谁有看法的，我洗耳恭听。
Let's throw it out
and see if the cat licks it up.
大家各抒己见，看看猫咪喜不喜欢。
- The cat licks it up?
- 猫咪喜不喜欢？
- Yeah. The boy...
- 呃，那小孩……
Look how dark it's gettin' out there.
I bet we're gonna have a storm now.
看，外面变得很暗了。我敢打赌要下暴雨了。
Boy, oh boy. It's really hot, huh?
同志啊同志，热死人了，是吧？
- Pardon me, but... don't you ever sweat?
- 别怪我多嘴，不过……你没出汗吗？
- No, I don't.
- 没有。
Listen. I... I was wonderin' if...
听我说，我……我在想是不是……
Maybe... maybe we should
take another vote.
或许……或许我们应该再投一次票。
Great. Maybe we can follow this one up
with a little dancing and refreshments!
太棒了。也许我们可以来场小型舞会和娱乐！
- Mr Foreman?
- 组长同志？
- Well, that's OK with me.
- 呃，我没意见。
Anyone doesn't wanna vote?
Hey, come on.
谁不愿意投票的？嗨，把它灭了。
- Sorry.
- 抱歉。
- I think we ought to have an open ballot.
- 我认为我们应该进行公开投票。
Call out our votes, you know?
Let's see who stands where.
挨个唱票，看看各自的立场。
Well, that sounds fair to me.
Anyone object?
好吧，我觉得可以。有人反对吗？
OK. I'll call off your jury numbers. One?
好，我喊大家的编号。1号？
Oh, that's me. I vote guilty. Two?
噢，我就是。我认为有罪。2号？
Not guilty.
无罪。
Number three?
3号？
Guilty.
有罪。
Number four?
4号？
Guilty.
有罪。
Number five?
5号？
Not guilty.
无罪。
Number six?
6号？
Not guilty.
无罪。
Number seven?
7号？
Guilty.
有罪。
Number eight?
8号。
Not guilty.
无罪。
- Number nine?
- 9号？
- Not guilty.
- 无罪。
- Number ten?
- 10号？
- Guilty.
- 有罪。
Number eleven?
11号？
Not guilty.
无罪。
Number twelve?
12号？
Number twelve!
12号！
Guilty.
有罪。
The vote is now six to six.
投票结果是6比6.
And we go into extra innings here, eh?
我们要进入加时赛了吗，啊？
Six to six! I'm telling you, some of you
people in here must be out of your minds.
6比6！我告诉你们，你们有些人脑子真是进水了。
A kid like that!
像这种小子！
I don't think the kind of boy he is
has anything to do with it.
我不认为他是哪类人跟这件案子有什么瓜葛。
- Facts determine the case.
- 要以事实为基础。
- Don't give me that!
- 少跟我来这套！
I'm sick and tired of facts.
You can twist 'em any way you like.
我讨厌谈什么事实。你们连事实都可以随心所欲歪曲。
That's exactly the point
this gentleman has been making.
事实就是这位同志刚刚说的。
You keep shouting
at the top of your lungs...
你就会歇斯底里……
I'd like to be a few years younger.
That man gets on my...
真希望我再年轻几岁。这家伙比我……
- My, it's hot in here.
- 我的，这里很热。
- Want a drink of water?
- 要喝水吗？
No, no. Thanks. Thanks.
不用，不用了，谢谢，谢谢。
- It's gonna rain.
- 要下雨了。
- Well, how'd you figure that out, killer?
- 哼，你怎么知道的，凶手？
- How come you changed your vote?
- 你怎么改变你的投票了呢？
- It just seemed there was room for doubt.
- 因为好像还有疑问。
- You haven't got a leg to stand on.
- 你连插一腿的地方都没有。
- I don't feel that way.
- 我不这么看。
- A lot of details never came out.
- 有很多细节没弄清楚。
- Yeah, well, good luck.
- 那好，祝你好运。
Come on. You're like everybody else.
You think too much, you get mixed up.
拜托，你和其他人一个德性。你想太多了，就糊涂了。
- You know what I mean?
- 明白我的意思吗？
- I don't think you have any right to...
- 我认为你没有权利……
Loudmouth.
大嗓门。
Look at that come down, will ya?
看看那下着的雨。
You know, this reminds me
of a storm we had last...
这让我想起了上次的暴雨……
Was it November?
I don't know. Something.
是11月份吗？记不清了。
It was quite a storm we had.
It was right in the middle of a game.
那真是场大暴雨啊。正好是比赛中场。
We were behind-seven to six. We'd just
started to move the ball, made a tackle.
我们落后了――7比6.正当我们拿到球，准备来个擒抱摔倒。
It was gonna cut right in, slash through,
slashed right in, cut right through...
从右插进去，穿过，再右穿，右插过去……
And...
呃……
We had this kid - Slattery.
我们有个叫Slatttery的。
He was an ox. A real ox.
力大如牛，真的。
I wish I had another one just like him.
要是当时还有一个像他这样的就完美了。
I forgot to tell you. I'm the assistant head
coach at Andrew J McCorkle High School.
我忘了跟你说了，我是J mCcORKLE中学的的助理教练。
That's out in Queens.
在Queens城的郊外。
And anyway... we're starting
to move along real nice.
不管怎样……正当我们组织漂亮的进攻，
You know, their whole line is just...
just comin' apart.
对方的防线全线崩溃……
And it starts to come down,
cats and dogs, just like this.
老天突然下起了雨，倾盆大雨，就像这样。
Just... whoosh! You know, right down.
就是……哗哗地下！
Well, it was murder, you know?
呃，罪名是成立的，你知道的。
I swear, I... I nearly bawled.
Just... We couldn't go nowhere.
我发誓，我……我都快喊起来了。
就因为……我们哪里都攻不破了。
Hey, what is it with this fan here?
How come...
嗨，这风扇出什么毛病了？怎么……
Must have been
on the same switch with the lights.
肯定是和这些灯是一条线路的。
Well, things are lookin' up here, huh?
呃，看看这儿，哈？
Yeah.
嗯。
Boy, that's better.
同志们，好多了。
Hey! Two points.
嗨，2分。
You guys ever go to the Garden?
你们去过那个公园吗？
That's a damn stupid thing to do.
别干这蠢事了。
Oh, I'm sorry. I...
噢，不好意思，我……
You know?
你知道的。
Pardon me.
抱歉。
Well, how do you like it? Even-steven.
Pretty surprising, isn't it?
呃，你觉得怎样？平分秋色，出人意料，是不是？
Yes.
是啊。
That... business before, when that tall guy,
whatshisname, was tryin' to bait me?
那……在此之前，那个高个子，叫什么名来着，试图激怒我？
That doesn't prove anything.
I'm a... pretty excitable person.
那根本证明不了什么。我是一个……很容易动怒的人。
Where does he come off
calling me a public avenger, a sadist?
他什么时候遂了他的愿了，叫我公众复仇人，施虐逛？
Anyone in his right mind
would blow his stack.
他简直是哪根神经搭错了。
He was just tryin' to bait me.
他就是故意激怒我。
He did an excellent job.
他表现很出色。
I think we're going nowhere here.
我觉得我们已经进了死胡同了。
I'm ready to walk into court
and declare a hung jury.
我准备去法庭宣布陪审团意见分歧。
- There's no point in this thing going on.
- 再继续下去也不会有个水落石出。
- I go for that, too.
- 我也去。
Let the kid take his chance
with 12 other guys.
让这小子试试其他12个人的运气吧。
The judge won't accept a hung jury.
We haven't been here long.
法官不会同意陪审团意见分歧的。规定的时间还没到。
- Well, let's find out.
- 那好，我们把它弄清楚。
- I am not in favour of that.
- 我不赞成。
This kid wouldn't stand a chance
with another jury, and you know it.
换陪审团，这小子还是要倒霉，你清楚的。
Come on, we're hung.
Nobody's gonna change his vote.
好了，我们分歧很大，没人会改变立场的。
- Still no room for reasonable doubt?
- 还是不存在合理怀疑吗？
- No.
- 不存在。
Pardon. Maybe you don't fully understand
the term "reasonable doubt".
等等，可能是你没有充分理解“合理怀疑”的意思。
What do you mean, I don't understand?
你什么意思，我不理解？
How do you like this guy?
I'm tellin' you, they're all alike.
你觉得这人怎么样？我就跟你说过，
他们是一丘之貉。
They come over here
and before they can take a breath,
他们铺天盖地过来，没喘息之前，
they're telling us how to run the show.
就跟我们说怎么演这出戏。
- Boy, the arrogance of this guy!
- 同志，这家伙太自以为是了。
- All right.
- 好了。
Let's stop the arguing
for about two minutes in here.
不要再吵了，休息二分钟。
Now, who's got
something constructive to say?
现在，谁可以谈点有建议性的？
I'd like to go over something,
if you gentlemen don't mind.
我们不要再纠缠于某些东西了，如果你们不介意。
An important point
for the prosecution was
检方的一个重要观点是
the fact that after the boy claimed he was
at the movies when the killing took place,
被告人称案发时他正在电影院，
he couldn't remember the names
of the movies or who starred in them.
而他记不清电影的名字或是由谁主演的事实。
- This gentleman has made that point.
- 这位同志已经提到这点。
- That's correct.
- 没错。
It's the only alibi the boy offered, and
he couldn't back it up with any details.
这是被告人提供的唯一不在场证明，但是他
不能提供详细信息予以支持。
In the boy's place,
do you think you could remember details
站在被告人的立场，你觉得你能记得住细节
after an upsetting experience
such as being slapped by your father?
在被你老爸掌掴等这些不快经历后。
I think so, if there were
any special details to remember.
我认为我可以，如果有特殊的细节可以记忆。
The boy couldn't remember the movies
because he wasn't there.
被告人记不得电影是因为他根本就没去过。
According to the police testimony,
the boy was questioned in the kitchen,
按照警方的证明，被告人当时是在厨房接受询问的，
while the body of his father
was lying in the bedroom.
而他老爸的尸体躺在卧室。
Do you think
you could remember details under those circumstances?
你觉得在这种情形下你能记住细节?
- I do.
- 我可以。
- Under great emotional stress?
- 心里压力很大的情况下？
- Under great emotional stress.
- 心里压力很大的情况下。
- He remembered them correctly in court.
- 他在法庭上记得很清楚。
Yes. His lawyer took great pains
to bring that out.
没错，他的律师很不情愿提到这些。
He had three months to the day of the trial
in which to memorise them.
在审判前他有三个月的时间去记忆。
It's not difficult for a lawyer to find out
what played on a particular night.
律师找出当晚发生什么事情，并不是什么难事。
I'll take the testimony
from right after the murder,
要是我，案发后就立即获取证物，
when he couldn't remember a thing about
the movies, great emotional stress or not.
他记不清关于电影，不管有没有很大的心理压力。
- I'd like to ask you a personal question.
- 我想问一下你私人问题。
- Go ahead.
- 问吧。
- Where were you last night?
- 昨晚你在哪？
- I was home all night.
- 我一晚上都在家。
- How about the night before that?
- 前天晚上呢？
- What is this?
- 这要干嘛？
It's all right. I left the office at 8.30
and went straight home and to bed.
没事。我8：30离开办公室，直接回家，然后睡觉。
- And the night before that?
- 大前天呢？
- That was... Tuesday night.
- 那是……星期二晚上。
- The bridge tournament. I played bridge.
- 桥牌联赛，我玩桥牌。
- Monday night?
- 星期一晚上呢？
When you get to
New Year's Eve 1954, let me know.
问到1954年除夕，就告我一声。
Monday night? Monday night...
my wife and I went to the movies.
星期一晚上？星期一晚上……
我和我爱人去看电影了。
- What did you see?
- 看了什么电影？
- The Scar/et Circ/e. A whodunit.
- 《大红圈》，侦探片。
- What was the second feature?
- 还看了什么片？
- The...
- 有……
I'll tell you in a minute. The...
我一会儿告诉你。有……
Remarkab/e Mrs...
著名的……
Something.
什么。
Mrs Bainbridge.
The Remarkab/e Mrs Bainbridge.
《Bainbrigde夫人》。《著名的Bainbrigde夫人》。
I saw that. It's called
The Amazing Mrs Bainbridge.
我看过。那是《不可思议的Bainbrigde夫人》。
Yes. The Amazing Mrs Bainbridge.
是的，《不可思议的Bainbrigde夫人》。
Who was in
The Amazing Mrs Bainbridge?
《不可思议的Bainbrigde夫人》里有谁？
Barbara... Long, I think it was.
Barbara……Long，应该是。
A dark, very pretty girl.
非常漂亮的一个黑发女孩。
- Ling or... Long. Something like that.
- Ling或是……Long。差不多是这样。
- Who else?
- 还有谁？
I'd never heard of them before.
我以前没听说过他们。
It was a very inexpensive
second feature, with unknown...
第二部片子但不贵，有不知名的……
And you weren't under
an emotional stress, were you?
你没有心理压力吧，有吗？
No.
没有。
I wasn't.
我没有。
- I think the point is made.
- 我觉得可以说明问题了。
- Big point.
- 说明个屁啊。
You can talk till your tongue is
draggin' on the floor. The boy is guilty.
等你舌头拖地了你再说吧。这小子有罪。
Know what I mean, my friend?
明白我的意思吗，同志？
- You got those cough drops?
- 你还有止咳糖吗？
- They're all gone, my friend.
- 吃完了，同志。
Oh, boy. Look at that rain.
There goes your ball game.
同志，看看这雨。你的球队要打水战了。
It's only a shower.
这只不过是沐浴而已。
Besides, they got the infield covered.
再说了，他们内场有顶蓬呢。
Say, could I see that knife
a second, please?
请问我能看看那把刀吗？
Well, we're still tied up six to six.
Who's got a suggestion?
现在还是6比6，谁有什么破解方法？
- It's 5 after 6. Let's get some dinner.
- 6：05了，我们吃点东西吧。
- Why don't we wait till 7 o'clock?
- 7点再吃不行吗？
OK with me.
我没问题。
There's something I'd like to say.
It's been bothering me a little,
我想说一下，这困扰我很久了，
and as long as we're stuck...
既然我们陷入了僵局……
There was this whole business about
the stab wound and how it was made.
就是关于伤口及它是怎样形成的。
- The downward angle of it, you know?
- 它的角度是向下的。
- Don't start with that again.
- 不要再提这事了。
- They've been over it and over it.
- 已经反反复复说过多遍。
- I know, but I don't go along with it.
- 我知道，但是我并不赞同。
The boy was five feet seven inches tall.
His father was six two.
被告人高5尺7，而他父亲是6尺2.
That's a difference of seven inches.
两人相差7寸。
It's very awkward to stab down into the
chest of someone over half a foot taller.
刺比自己高半尺多的人是很难下手的。
Give me that.
把刀给我。
I'll give you a demonstration.
Somebody get up.
我来做个示范。谁站起来试试。
Watch this - I don't wanna
have to do it again.
瞧好了――我可不会再做一次。
I'll make myself about
six or seven inches shorter.
我要矮个6到7英寸。
- That's about right. Maybe a little more.
- 差不多，可能还要矮一点儿。
- OK, a little more.
- 好，再低一点儿。
Now... nobody's hurt.
呃……没人会受伤的。
- Right?
- 对吧？
- Right. Nobody hurt.
- 对，没人会受伤的。
Now, this is the way I'd stab a man
who was... taller than I was.
我就是这样刺一个比我高的人的。
Look at the angle. Down and in.
就是这个角度，刺下去。
And this is the way it was done.
Now tell me I'm wrong.
就是这样。现在告诉我有什么问题吧。
- Down and in. There's no argument.
- 刺下去，没问题啊。
- Hold on a minute.
- 等一等。
Will you give me that?
能把刀给我吗？
Boy, I hate these things.
同志，我讨厌这种东西。
- Did you ever see a knife fight?
- 你见过械斗吗？
- No.
- 没见过。
Anybody here ever see a knife fight?
有人见过械斗吗？
Well, I have. You know, on my back stoop,
the lot across the street, back yard.
我见过。在我家后廊，临街的地方，就是后院。
Switchblades came
with the neighbourhood.
邻居们手持弹簧刀。
Funny I never thought of it before.
I guess you try to forget these things.
我从未见过这种场面。我想你们也不想见识那场面的。
- How do you use a switchblade?
- 你怎么用弹簧刀呢？
- Well, you'd never use it like this.
- 不是这么拿的。
See, you'd lose too much time
switching hands.
看见了吗，换个手势要花很多时间。
Here's how. Underhand.
是这么拿的。手放下面。
Anyone who's ever used one
wouldn't handle it any other way.
用过弹簧刀的人不会有其他握法。
- Are you sure?
- 你确定？
- I'm sure.
- 我确定。
- It's why they're made to open like that.
- 弹簧刀就是这么弹出来的。
- The boy was pretty handy with a knife?
- 被告人对刀很熟手吧？
You think he could have made
the wound that killed his father?
你认为他能弄出那个伤口，杀害他的父亲吗？
No. Not with the experience he got
all his life handling these things.
不能。他玩了半辈子的刀，不会这么玩的。
- I feel he'd have gone for him underhand.
- 我感觉他比较喜欢手放下面。
- How do you know?
- 你怎么知道？
- Were you there when he was killed?
- 案发时你在现场吗？
- No. Neither was anybody else.
- 不在，现场也没有其他人。
What are you giving us this
mumbo jumbo for? I don't believe it.
那你胡言乱语什么？我不相信。
I don't think you can tell
what wound he might have made
我认为你想不出他还能弄出什么样的伤口
simply because he knew
how to handle a knife.
因为他对刀玩得很熟。
- What do you think?
- 你怎么看？
- I don't know.
- 不知道。
- What do you mean, you don't know?
- 你不知道，你什么意思？
- I don't know.
- 就是不知道啊。
- How about you?
- 你叫？
- I don't know about the rest of 'em,
- 我不知道其他人怎么想，
but I'm gettin' tired of this
yakety-yakkin'. It's gettin' us nowhere.
但我已经不耐烦了。说来说去有个屁用。
So I guess /'// have to break it up.
I'm changin' my vote to not guilty.
所以我想我要打破这个僵局。我改投无罪票。
- You're what?
- 你说啥？
- You heard me. I've had enough.
- 你没听见吗？我受够了。
- You've had enough? That's no answer.
- 你受够了？还没弄个水落石出呢。
- Listen, you just take care of yourself.
- 听着，你只关心你自个儿。
- You know?
- 知道吗？
- He's right.
- 他说的没错。
That's not an answer.
还没弄个水落石出呢。
What kind of a man are you?
你这算什么？
You have sat here and voted
guilty with everyone else
你坐在这，和其他人认为有罪
because there are some baseball tickets
burning a hole in your pocket.
就因为买了张球票，你就火烧屁股了。
Now you have changed your vote because
you say you're sick of all the talking?
现在你改变主意是因为你已经厌烦大家的讨论了？
- Now, listen, buddy...
- 你听好，同志……
- Who tells you that you have the right
- 谁告诉你你有权利
to play like this with a man's life?
Don't you care...
视他人生命如儿戏？难道你不关心……
Now, wait a minute.
You can't talk like that to me.
等等，你无权这么跟我说话。
I can talk like that to you.
If you want to vote not guilty,
我就能这么跟你说话。如果你想投无罪票，
do it because you are convinced he is not
guilty, not because you've had enough.
如果你是被说服了，那就投无罪，而不是你受够了。
And if you think he is guilty,
then vote that way.
如果你认为有罪，那就表里如一。
Or don't you have the guts
to do what you think is right?
难道你连自己认为什么是对的，也没勇气去做吗？
- Now, listen...
- 听着……
- Guilty or not guilty?
- 有罪还是无罪？
- I told you. Not guilty.
- 我说了，无罪。
- Why?
- 理由呢？
- Look, I don't have to...
- 我没义务……
- You do have to. Say it. Why?
- 你有义务。说出你的理由。
I... I don't think he's guilty.
我……我不认为他有罪。
- I want another vote.
- 我想再投一次票。
- OK, that's another vote called for.
-好，再投一次。
I guess the quickest way
is a show of hands. Anyone object?
举手表决最快，有人反对吗？
OK, all those voting not guilty,
raise your hands.
好，认为无罪的举手。
One, two, three,
1、2、3、
four, five, six, seven...
4、5、6、7……
eight.
Nine.
All those voting guilty, raise your hands.
认为有罪的举手。
One, two, three.
1、2、3
Well, the vote's nine to three
in favour of acquittal.
投票结果是9票无罪，3票有罪。
I don't understand you people!
我真搞不懂你们这些人！
All these picky little points you keep
bringing up, they don't mean nothing!
你们提出的这些鸡毛蒜皮，毫无意义！
You saw this kid just like I did.
你们和我都见过那小子。
Don't tell me you believe that
phoney story about losing the knife
别跟我说你相信把刀弄丢、
and about being at the movies.
去了电影院的鬼话。
Look, you know how these people lie.
It's born in them.
你们知道谎是怎么撒的，他们天生就是骗子。
What the heck? I don't have to tell you.
They don't know what the truth is!
见鬼了？我没必要跟你们多说。他们都不知道什么是真相！
And they don't need any real big reason
to kill someone, either.
他们杀人也不需要师出有名。
No, sir. They get drunk.
They're real big drinkers, all of 'em.
不，同志们，他们喝高了。他们都是酒鬼，都是。
You know that. And bang!
Someone's lying in the gutter.
你们都知道的。砰，有的就掉进阴沟。
Nobody's blaming 'em.
That's the way they are by nature.
没人怪罪他们。他们天生如此。
You know what I mean? Violent.
Where are you going?
你们知道我的意思，暴力。你要去哪？
Human life don't mean
as much to them as it does to us.
他们就是贱命一条，跟咱们不同。
They're lushing it up
and fighting all the time,
他们喝成烂泥，整天打打杀杀，
and if somebody gets killed,
somebody gets killed! They don't care!
而要是有人被要小命，要了小命，他们根本不在乎！
Sure, there's some good things about 'em,
too. I'm the first one to say that.
当然，他们也有好的一面。我第一个就说了。
I've known a couple who were OK,
but that's the exception.
我也知道有几个还凑合，不也那也是例外。
Most of 'em, it's like they have
no feelings! They can do anything!
他们大部分麻木不仁，嘛事儿都干得出来！
What's going on here?
大家怎么了啊？
I'm trying to tell you.
You're making a big mistake, you people.
我在跟你们说呢。你们犯了个大错。
This kid is a liar. I know it.
I know all about them.
这小子就是个骗子。我知道。我了解他们。
Listen to me. They're no good.
听我说。他们都是歪瓜劣枣。
There's not a one of 'em who's any good.
他们中间没一个好货。
I mean, what's happening in here?
大家这是怎么了？
I speak my piece, and you...
我在发表我的看法，但你们……
Listen to me.
听我说。
I... We're... we're...
我……我们……我们是……
This kid on trial here. His type.
Well, don't you know about them?
接受审判的被告人，他那种人。难道你们不了解这种人吗？
There's a... There's a danger here.
这……这很危险啊。
These people are dangerous.
这类人是危险分子。
They're... wild.
他们很……野蛮。
Listen to me. Listen to me.
听我说。听我说。
I have. Now, sit down
and don't open your mouth again.
我有听。坐下，免开尊口。
Some of the time... I tell you.
有时候……我告诉你们。
It's always difficult to keep personal
prejudice out of a thing like this.
对这种事情很难不掺杂个人偏见。
Wherever you run into it,
prejudice always obscures the truth.
不管何时碰上，偏见总会模糊真相。
I don't really know what the truth is.
我不太清楚真相是什么。
I don't suppose anybody
will ever really know.
我也不认为有谁能够真的知道。
Nine of us now seem to feel
that the defendant is innocent.
我们九个认为被告人是无辜的。
But we're just gambling on
probabilities. We may be wrong.
但我们只是在赌可能性。我们可能犯错。
We may be trying to let a guilty man
go free. I don't know. Nobody really can.
我们可能会放纵一个戴罪之人。我不知道。没人可以。
But we have a reasonable doubt.
但我们有合理怀疑。
And that's something
that's very valuable in our system.
那是我们这个制度里非常宝贵的东西。
No jury can declare a man guilty
unless it's sure.
除非确信，陪审团不能认定一个人有罪。
We nine can't understand
how you three are still so sure.
我们九个不理解为何你们仨还是那么确定。
- Maybe you can tell us.
- 或许你能告诉我们。
- I'll try.
- 我试试。
You've made some excellent points,
but I still believe the boy is guilty.
你有些说的很有道理，但是我还是坚信他是有罪的。
I have two reasons. One: The evidence
given by the woman across the street,
两个理由。一：目击案发过程的街对过的女人
who actually saw the murder committed.
提供的证据。
That's the most important testimony.
这是最有力的证据。
And two: The fact that
she described the stabbing
二：她说她看见被告人
by saying she saw the boy
raise his arm over his head
行刺时手臂高过其父
and stab down into the father's chest.
接着往下刺入他的胸口。
- She saw him do it, the wrong way.
- 她看见他行刺了，方式并不正确。
- That's absolutely right.
- 完全正确。
Let's talk about this woman for a moment.
我们讨论一下这个女人。
She said she went to bed
about eleven o'clock that night.
她说她当晚是11点钟上的床。
Her bed was next to the window,
and she could look out
她的床靠窗，她能够往外看
and see directly into
the boy's room across the street.
直接看到街对面被告人的房间。
She tossed and turned for over an hour.
她辗转了一小时也没入睡。
Finally, she turned toward the window
at about 10 minutes after 12,
最后，她在0：10左右转向窗口方向，
and as she looked out, she saw the killing
through the windows of a passing el train.
就在她往外看时，正好透过轻轨的窗户看见行凶。
She said the lights went out
after the killing,
她说杀人后灯都灭了，
but that she got a good look at the boy
in the act of stabbing his father.
但她能够看清被告人行凶的过程。
As far as I can see it,
this is unshakeable testimony.
在我看来，这是铁证。
- Well, that's the whole case.
- 整个过程就是这样。
- What do you think?
- 你怎么看？
How about you?
你呢？
I don't know. So much evidence to sift.
This is a pretty complicated business.
我不知道。这么多证据要筛选，这事很棘手。
Frankly, I don't see how
you can vote for acquittal.
坦率地讲，我不明白你怎么投无罪票。
- It's not so easy to arrange the evidence.
- 理清这些证据并不简单。
- Throw out all the other evidence!
- 别管别的证据！
The woman saw him do it!
What else do you want?
那女人看见他杀人了！你还要怎样？
- Well, maybe...
- 可能……
- Let's vote on it.
- 我们投票。
OK, there's another vote called for.
Anyone object?
好吧，有人要求投票。有反对的吗？
All right. I'm changing my vote.
vb吧，我改变我的观点。
- He's guilty.
- 有罪。
- Anybody else? The vote is eight to four.
- 还有谁吗？8：4.
Why is this such a personal triumph
for you, this one vote?
区区一票，对你来说是就这么重要吗？
OK. I say we're a hung jury.
I say we take it in to the judge.
我认为陪审团意见不一致，应该提交给法官。
How about it? I wanna hear arguments.
着什么急？我要听听说法。
You, you're the leader of the cause.
What about it?
你是始作俑者，你怎么看？
- Let's go over it again.
- 我们再讨论一下。
- We've been over it again.
- 已经讨论一遍了。
The boy in the grey flannel suit is
bouncin' back and forth like a tennis ball.
穿灰绒衣服的家伙像根墙头草，两边倒。
There's no point in getting nasty.
You keep trying to turn this into a contest.
没人要把这事弄得乌烟瘴气，就你非得把它整得纷争不已。
OK.
好。
Maybe we can talk about
setting some kind of time limit.
或许我们可以设定时限。
Yeah. Once around for the deal, huh?
对，一局定生死，怎么样？
It's... a quarter after six. Someone
before mentioned seven o'clock.
现在是……6：15，刚有人说7点。
That's a point at which we might begin to
discuss whether we're a hung jury or not.
那时我们可以讨论是否要决定意见统不统一。
- Don't you feel well?
- 你不舒服吗？
- I feel perfectly well, thank you.
- 没什么不舒服的，谢谢。
I was saying seven o'clock
would be a reasonable time...
我刚说7点是个合理的时间……
The reason I asked that was because
you were rubbing your nose like...
我问你的原因是你揉鼻子像是……
Oh, I'm sorry for interrupting.
噢，不好意思打断你。
But you made a gesture
that reminded me of something.
但是你的动作让我想起一些事儿。
- I'm trying to settle something here.
- 我要解决问题。
- Well, I think this is important.
- 但我认为这很重要。
Thank you. Now, then.
I'm sure you'll pardon me for this,
谢谢。我相信你会谅解我的，
but I was wondering why
you rub your nose like that.
但我纳闷你为什么要那样揉鼻梁。
Come on, will you?
快点儿，求你了。
At this point I happen to be talking
to the gentleman sitting next to you.
我现在在同你旁边的同志说话。
Now, why were you
rubbing your nose like that?
你为什么要那样揉你的鼻梁呢？
If it's any of your business, I was
rubbing it because it bothers me a little.
如果这关系到你，我可以告诉你是因为这弄得我不舒服。
Oh, I'm sorry. Is it...
Is it because of your eyeglasses?
抱歉，那……那是因为你的眼镜吗？
It is. Now could we get on
to something else?
没错。现在我们能说其他的了吗？
Your eyeglasses made those two deep
impressions on the sides of your nose.
你的眼镜在你鼻子两边压出了两道深深的痕。
I hadn't noticed that before.
That must be annoying.
我之前没注意到。那肯定不舒服。
It is very annoying.
非常不舒服。
I wouldn't know about that.
I've never worn eyeglasses. 20/20.
我本来是不知道的。我还没戴过眼镜。两边各20.
Listen, will you come on already
with the optometrist bit?
你验过光吗？
The woman who testified
that she saw the killing
作证说她看见杀人的女人
had those same marks
on the sides of her nose.
在她鼻子两边也有这样的印痕。
Holy smoke! He's right.
天啊！他说的没错。
Please. Just give me a minute...
and I'll be finished.
请给我一分钟……我很快就说完。
I don't know if anyone else
noticed that about her.
我不知道其他人有没有注意到这点。
I didn't think of it then, but I've been
going over her face... in my mind.
我没想过，不过我印象中我注意过她的脸。
She had those same marks.
She kept rubbing them in court.
她也有这样的印痕，她在法庭上总是习惯性地去揉。
He's right. She did do that a lot.
没错，她经常性的动作。
This woman was about 45 years old.
这女的45岁上下。
She was making
a tremendous effort to look 35.
她极力表现得像个35的。
For her first public appearance.
Heavy make-up. Dyed hair.
对她的第一印象是浓妆，染头发。
Brand-new clothes that should have
been worn by a younger woman.
适合年轻女的穿的新衣服。
No glasses. Well, women do that.
See if you can get a mental picture of her.
不戴眼镜。女的都这样。想想你对她的印象。
What do you mean, no glasses? How do
you know whether she wore glasses?
你什么意思？不戴眼镜？你怎么知道她不戴？
- Just cos she was rubbin' her nose?
- 就因为她揉鼻子？
- She had those marks. I saw 'em.
- 她是有两道痕，我看见了。
- So? What do you think that means?
- 那又怎么了？你觉得那说明什么？
- I'm sick of your yellin'...
- 我讨厌你大声嚷嚷……
Come on. Forget it.
算了，算了。
Hey, listen. Listen, he's right. I saw
them too. I was the closest one to her.
嗨，听我说，听我说，他说的没错。我也看见了。
我离她最近。
She had these things
on the side of her nose.
她鼻梁两边是有两道痕。
What point are you makin'?
你说的什么话？
She had dyed hair, marks on her nose.
What does that mean?
她染发、鼻梁有痕，那说明什么呢？
Could those marks be made
by anything other than eyeglasses?
除了眼镜，还会是其他的压痕吗？
No. They couldn't.
不会，不可能是其他。
I didn't see any marks!
我没看见什么压痕！
I did. Strange,
but I didn't think about it before.
我确实看见了。奇怪，但我之前没想过这事儿。
Why didn't the lawyer say something?
那律师怎么没说什么？
There are twelve people in here
concentrating on this case.
我们十二个人在讨论这个案子，
- Eleven of us didn't think of it either.
- 11个人都没注意到。
- What about the district attorney?
- 那检察官呢？
You think he'd pull that?
Have her testify without her glasses?
你觉得他会提出来吗？她不是没戴眼镜作证吗？
Ever see a woman who didn't want to
wear them because they spoil her looks?
见过女的不愿意戴眼镜，因为这损坏她们的形象？
OK. She had marks on her nose.
I'm givin' you that.
好，她鼻梁上有压痕。我承认这点。
From glasses, right? She didn't
wanna wear 'em out of the house
眼镜弄的，是吧？她不戴出房间
so people'd think she's gorgeous.
这样别人觉得她很端庄漂亮。
But when she saw this kid killin'
his father, she was in the house alone.
但她看见案发过程时，她正好一个人呆在房间。
That's all.
就是这样。
Do you wear glasses when you go to bed?
你戴眼镜睡觉吗？
No. I don't.
不，我不会。
No one wears eyeglasses to bed.
没人会戴着眼镜去睡觉。
It's logical to assume
that she wasn't wearing them in bed.
她没戴眼镜上床，这样推断才符合逻辑。
- How do you know?
- 你怎么知道？
- I don't know. I'm guessing.
- 我不知道。我只是猜测。
I'm also guessing that she didn't put them
on when she looked out of the window.
我也猜测她往窗外看的时候就没戴眼镜。
She testified the killing
took place just as she looked out.
她说案发时她正好往外看。
The lights went off.
She didn't have time to put them on.
灯灭了，她又没时间戴上。
Here's another guess. She honestly
thought she saw the boy kill his father.
还有一种猜测。她认为自己看见了被告人行凶杀人。
- I say she only saw a blur.
- 我是说她只是看得很模糊。
- How do you know what she saw?
- 你怎么知道她看见什么呢？
How does he know all that? How
do you know what glasses she wore?
他怎么知道呢？你怎么知道她戴什么眼镜呢？
Maybe they were sunglasses! Maybe
she was far-sighted! What do you know?
也许那不过是太阳镜！也许她远视！你知道什么？
I only know the woman's eyesight
is in question now.
我只知道这女的视力现在受到质疑。
She had to be able to identify a person
60 feet away, at night, without glasses.
她得认出60尺开外的人，在晚上，不戴眼镜。
You can't send someone off
to die on evidence like that.
你不能让别人死在这种证据上。
Aw, don't give me that.
别跟我来这套。
- Might she not have made a mistake?
- 她不会犯错吗？
- No.
- 不会。
- It's not possible?
- 不可能吗？
- No, it's not possible.
- 不可能。
Is it possible?
有可能吗？
Not guilty.
无罪。
Do you think he's guilty?
你认为他有罪吗？
I think he's guilty.
有罪。
Do you?
你呢？
No.
无罪。
I'm convinced. Not guilty.
我被说服了。无罪。
- What's the matter with you?
- 你们怎么回事啊？
- I have a reasonable doubt now.
- 我现在有了合理怀疑。
- It's eleven to one.
- 11比1.
- What about all the other evidence?
- 那其他证据呢？
What about all that stuff? The...
The knife? The whole business?
所有这一切呢？这把刀？整个事件呢？
Well, you said we could
throw out all the other evidence.
你刚说了我们可以抛开其他所有的证据。
Well, what do we do now?
那我们现在怎么办？
You're alone.
你孤军一人了。
I don't care whether I'm alone or not.
It's my right.
我不在乎我是不是孤军。这是我的权利。
It's your right.
是你的权利。
Well, what do you want? I say he's guilty.
你想干嘛？我说他有罪。
- We want to hear your arguments.
- 我们想听听你的理由。
- I gave you my arguments.
- 我跟你们说了我的理由。
We're not convinced.
We want to hear them again.
我们不信服。我们要再听一遍。
We have as much time as it takes.
有的是时间。
Everything-every single thing that took
place in that courtroom says he's guilty.
所有一切――法庭上的每一细节都说明他有罪。
What do you think?
I'm an idiot or somethin'?
你以为呢？我是傻蛋还是什么？
Take that stuff about the old man,
who lived there and heard everything!
看看那老头，他住在那、都被他听到了。
Or this business about the knife.
They found another one exactly like it?
或者是那把刀。他们有找到其他一样的刀吗？
The old man saw him!
Right there, on the stairs.
那老头亲眼所见！就在那，在楼梯上。
What's the difference
how many seconds it was?
花多长秒有什么区别？
Every single thing. The knife
fallin' through a hole in his pocket.
每一细节 。刀从他口袋的洞里滑出来。
You can't prove he didn't get to the door!
你不能证明他没有到门口！
Sure, you can take all the time, hobble
around the room, but you can't prove it!
当然，你可以花所有的时间、满屋蹒跚，但你就是不能证明！
And what about this business of the el?
And the movies?
还有那列轻轨？还有电影？
There's a phoney deal if I ever heard one.
那是一个骗局。
I'll bet you $5,000
/'d remember the movies I saw.
我赌5000块，我会记得我看过的电影。
I'm tellin' you, everything that's gone on
has been twisted and turned!
我告诉你们，所有这一切都被歪曲了！
This business with the glasses?
How do you know she didn't have 'em on?
那副眼镜？你怎么知道她就没戴呢？
This woman testified in open court!
那女的在公开法庭上作证呢！
And what about
hearin' the kid yell? Huh?
还有杀人的叫喊？哈？
I'm tellin' ya, I've got all the facts here.
我告诉你们，事实我都清楚。
Here...
都清楚……
Well, that's it. That's the whole case.
那就是。那就是全部。
Well?
呃
Say something!
说点啥啊！
You lousy bunch of bleedin' hearts.
你们这帮没心没肺的东西。
You're not gonna intimidate me.
I'm entitled to my opinion.
你们吓不了我，我有权坚持自己的观点。
Rotten kids... You work your life out!
臭小子……你是死有余辜！
No...
不……
Not guilty.
无罪。
We're ready now.
我们准备好了。
Hey!
嗨！
- What's your name?
- 你怎么称呼？
- Davis.
- Davis
My name's McCardle.
我叫McCardle
- Well, so long.
- 呃，时间好长啊。
- So long.
- 好长哈。